<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>International conference on impacts of agricultural research and development: why has impact assessment research not made more of a difference?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Watson, D.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Costa Rica</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Agricultural resources</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental factors</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Economic situation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>International organizations</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policies</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Agricultural development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Economic growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Agricultural research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poverty</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Developing Countries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Human nutrition</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This documet-contains the proceedings of an international conference on impact assessment research held in San Jose, Costa Rica, from 4-7 February 2002. Co-organized by the Economics Program of the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT) and the Standing Panel on Impact Assessment (SPIA) of the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR), the conference was attended by approximately 150 impact assessment practitioners and users. Participants included representatives from CGIAR Centers, national agricultural research organizations, public and private universities, multilaterallending organizations, development assistance agencies, non-governmental organizations (NGOs), philanthropic foundations, private corporations, and the media. The goal of the conference was to examine why many impact assessment studies have had lirnited influence on the way that agricultural research is conducted and have failed to ensure adequate and sustainable financial support for research. Participants concluded that the success of future impact assessment studies could be improved by: (1) better matching impact assessment results to the needs of decision makers; (2) making impact assessments more credible and more understandable, without losing rigor; and (3) improving methods for assessing a broader array of impacts, beyond traditional econornic measures.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:10:22Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:10:22Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2003</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:isbn>970-648-104-4</dc:isbn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1040</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1040</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1040</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:51Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>