<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Viscoelastic characterization of glutenins in wheat kernels measured by creep tests</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hernandez-Estrada, Z.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Figueroa, J.D.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rayas-Duarte P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peña-Bautista, R.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Creep</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Compliance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>glutenin subunit</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kelvin?Voigt model</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Retardation time</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effect of high and low molecular weight glutenin subunits on viscoelastic properties of wheat kernels was investigated using creep tests with generalized Kelvin¨CVoigt model (r2 ¡Ö 0.94; P &lt; 0.0001). Glu-A1, Glu-B1 and Glu-D1 affected the creep coefficients in Glu-1 loci. Regarding LMW-GS, the locus Glu-A3 had highest influence on creep followed by Glu-B3; Glu-D3 did not showed differences. In general, the modulus of elasticity E0 ¡Ö 242 MPa and viscosity was ¦Ì0 ¡Ö 1.6 ¡Á 107 MPa¡¤s. Higher elastic moduli and viscosity were found in HMW-GS and LMW-GS of good quality compared to the poor quality performance genotypic groups. Samples with subunit Glu-A1 null presented lower elastic modulus and viscosity compared to Glu-A1 1 and 2&amp;#8727;. Glu-B1 13 + 16 presented higher elastic modulus and viscosity, which is associated with good quality performance. The elastic moduli, especially E0 were positively correlated with SDS-volume and rheological properties. This methodology can be applied to few kernels is easy, rapid, and nondestructive.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:55Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:55Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2012</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0260-8774</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2928</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0260877412002622</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2928</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2928</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:09Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>