<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Selection for drought tolerance increases maize yields across a range of nitrogen levels</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Banziger, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Edmeades, G.O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lafitte, H.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zea mays</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Selection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Injurious factors</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Drought</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nitrogen</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Application rates</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plant breeding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Drought resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research projects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>It is not known whether selection for improved tolerance to a specific abiotic stress leads to correlated changes in performance under other stresses. Drought and N deficiency are important constraints to production in the tropics. We examined the effect of selection for drought tolerance on performance of tropical maize (Zea mays L.) under a range of N levels. Original and advanced selections of four populations, improved for tolerance to midseason drought for two to eight recurrent selection cycles each, were evaluated in two experiments under severe N stress, one experiment under medium N stress, and two well-fertilized experiments. Nitrogen accumulated in the aboveground biomass at maturity averaged 52, 63, 105, 151, and 163 kg N ha&amp;#8722;1 in the five experiments, and grain yields of 3.0, 2.9, 5.2, 6.0, and 6.5 Mg ha&amp;#8722;1 were obtained. Selection for tolerance to midseason drought stress increased grain yields by an average of 86 kg ha&amp;#8722;1 yr&amp;#8722;1 with nonsignificantly larger gains under severe N stress (100 kg ha&amp;#8722;1 yr&amp;#8722;1). Drought-tolerant selections had increased biomass and N accumulation at maturity, the changes being largest under severe N stress. Additionally, drought-tolerant selection cycles were associated with delayed leaf senescence and an increased or unchanged N harvest index, indicating that leaf N was used more efficiently for grain production. Selection for tolerance to midseason drought stress appears to increase grain yield across a range of N stress levels and may lead to morphological and physiological changes that are of particular advantage under N stress.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:07:52Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:07:52Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1999</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1959</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1959</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1959</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:47Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>