<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Progress of wheat breeding in China and the future perspective</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xia Xian-Chun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chen Xin-Min</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhuang Qiao-Sheng</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>molecular marker</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>yield potential</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Disease resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>common wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>During the last ten years, Chinese wheat breeding has mainly made progresses in three aspects, i.e., (1) two sets of cultivars with high yielding potential, improved quality, and multi-resistance to various diseases were developed and extended, (2) three elite parents, viz. Zhou 8425B, Lumai 14, and 6VS/6AL translocation line played a leading role in cultivar development; and (3) a significant progress has been achieved in breeding methodology and applied research. Main constrains on wheat breeding were also summarized. The development and utilization of molecular markers such as SSR marker and functional maker, was reviewed from breeding point of view, and the priority areas for the next five to ten years were proposed. It summarized the progress of wheat quality study which is closely associated with cultivar development, including laboratory evaluation methods and selection criteria for pan bread, cookie, Chinese noodles and steamed bread. China?s strategies for wheat breeding were analyzed in four areas: (1) a draft points on improving Chinese wheat yield potential; (2) utilization of durable resistance for cultivar development; (3) more efforts on water use efficiency, tolerance to high temperature and traits associated with broad adaptation due to the serious impact of climate change; and (4) increased investment in breeding and seed marketing from private sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:49Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:49Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2011</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0496-3490</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2889</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>China</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1814991</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2889</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2889</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:07Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>