<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Insect pests of maize: a guide for field identification</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ortega Corona, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Mite control</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Identification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Insect control</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zea mays</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pest insects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pest mites</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Focusing mainly on the tropics and subtropics, this pocket-size guidebook is designed to help readers recognize insect pests of maize through 94 color photographs as well as descriptions of the damage caused by each pest, its appearance, life cycle, and geographical distribution. A table groups major insect pests according to the plant parts they attack and the stage in plant development at which attack occurs. A brief, selective list of beneficial insects is also included, with color photographs. The list is followed by a section outlining general principles and various approaches to insect control</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T04:34:31Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T04:34:31Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1987</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Guidelines and manuals</dc:type>
  <dc:isbn>968-6127-07-0</dc:isbn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/700</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>700</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_700</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:35Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>