<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Maize-poultry value chains in India: Implications for Research and Development</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hellin, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Erenstein, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>India</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>maize-poultry value chains</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>quality-protein maize (QPM)</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>smallholder farmers</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Contract farming</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Rapid growth of the poultry industry in India has caused an increased demand for maize (Zea mays L.). Poultry feed contains 60-65% of maize and approximately 50% of India's annual maize harvest of 19 million tons is used for poultry feed. This article reports on a qualitative study of maize-poultry value chains. It identifies bottlenecks in the value chains and highlights some of the impediments to the uptake of quality-protein maize (QPM; maize with elevated levels of the essential amino acids lysine and tryptophan), which is being heavily promoted by Indian maize breeders. Further research is needed to produce QPM varieties that outperform normal maize varieties and to work more closely with the poultry industry so that QPM value chains become more demand than supply-driven.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2009</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2166</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>India</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1269750</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>India</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1269750</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2166</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2166</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:54Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>