<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of puroindoline alleles on milling performance and qualities of Chinese noodles, steamed bread and pan bread in spring wheats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chen Feng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chen Dongsheng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang Chunli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang Yan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xia Xianchun</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Bread wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Puroindoline alleles</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>milling quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Chinese noodles</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>steamed bread</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>pan bread</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two trials with a total of 75 spring bread wheat cultivars and advanced lines, were used to evaluate single kernel characterization system hardness, puroindoline alleles, milling yield, flour ash content, flour colour, and end-use qualities for Chinese noodles, steamed bread and pan bread. The results indicated that all International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center hard wheat lines surveyed were Pina-D1b genotype, whereas Pinb-D1b was the most common allele in the remaining cultivars. Genotypes with Pinb-D1b possess significantly lower flour ash content and higher milling yield than those of genotypes with Pina-D1b. For steamed bread, mean scores for loaf volume, crumb colour, width, structure and total score of Pinb-D1b genotypes were significantly higher than those of genotypes with Pina-D1b and wild type. For Chinese fresh white noodles, means for noodle a*, colour score, viscoelasticity and total score with Pinb-D1b were significantly higher than those of Pina-D1b and wild type. Means of loaf volume, texture and total score for Pinb-D1b genotypes were significantly higher than those of Pina-D1b genotypes. This study further illustrated the superiority of the Pinb-D1b allele on milling and processing qualities for various end products and provides useful information for wheat quality improvement.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:02Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:02Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2007</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2567</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2567</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2567</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:11Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>