<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of a three-way interaction including multi-attributes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Varela, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crossa, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rane, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Joshi, A.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trethowan R.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Three-mode interaction</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>principal component analyses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The additive main effect and multiplicative interaction (AMMI) has been widely used for studying and interpreting genotype×environment interaction (GEI) in agricultural experiments using multi-environment trials (METs). When METs are performed across several years the interaction is referred to as a 3-mode (3-way) data array, inwhich the modes are genotypes, environments, and years. The 3-way array can be applied to other conditions or factors artificially created by the researcher, such as different sowing dates or plant densities, etc. Three-way interaction data can be studied using the AMMI analysis. The objective of this study is to apply the 3-mode AMMI to 2 datasets. Dataset 1 comprises genotype (25)×location (4)×sowing time (4) interaction; 8 traits were measured. The structure of dataset 2 is genotype (20)×irrigation regimes (4)×year (3) on grain yield. Results of the 3-way AMMI on dataset 1 show that several important 3-way interactions were not detected when condensing location (4)×sowing time (4) into environments (16). An alternative 3-way array, genotype×attribute×locations for the early sowing date in Year 1, is considered. Results of the 3-way AMMI on dataset 2 show that different patterns of response of genotypes can be found at different irrigation methods and years.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:29Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:29Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2006</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1711</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1711</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1711</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:45Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>