<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quantifying and valuing the joint production of grain and fodder from maize fields: Evidence from Northern Pakistan</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Byerlee, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Iqbal, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fischer, K.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Grain feed</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feed crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Agroclimatology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal feeding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zea mays</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pakistan</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Simple methods are proposed for measuring the relative importance of grain and fodder produced jointly from maize fields in four zones in northern Pakistan. These methods suggest that the joint production of grain and fodder from maize is important in all four zones and that fodder accounts for between one-third and one-half of the total value of the crop. The relative value of fodder production is particularly high in two of the zones (the irrigated mid-altitude Swat Valley and the rainfed low altitude Islamabad District), both characterized by a high ratio of animal numbers:maize area. The results suggest that maize research and extension recommendations that do not take into consideration the fact that farmers produce maize for fodder as well as grain will often not be accepted by farmers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:14Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:14Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1989</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0014-4797</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1981</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayAbstract?fromPage=online&amp;aid=1615292</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Pakistan</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1168579</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Pakistan</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1168579</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1981</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1981</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:53Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>