<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farmers' willingness to pay for index based crop insurance in Pakistan: a case study on food and cash crops of rain-fed areas</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Akhter, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cash crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>willingness to pay</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>index based insurance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>rain-fed, Pakistan</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In Pakistan, agriculture is vulnerable to multiple risks, especially in the rain-fed areas. The crop insurance can serve as a useful tool to manage risks in the rain-fed areas of Pakistan. This study has assessed farmers? willingness to pay for insurance in the rain-fed areas of Pakistan by conducting a survey of 531 farmers in the Soon valley and Talagang areas of Pakistan. The farmers? willingness to pay for the index based crop insurance has been studied by employing the different econometric models. It has been found that these rain-fed areas consider indexed based insurance to be an important risk management strategy. The empirical results have indicated that farmers? economic status, household assets and membership of community organization are the important determinants of their willingness to pay a higher insurance premium. The propensity score matching results have revealed that farmers were satisfied with index based insurance and were also willing to increase the area under food as well as cash crops. This study has suggested that to make agricultural insurance scheme more successful, the government should provide subsidy which will help in increasing the area under food and cash crops and shall ensure food security in the region.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T17:57:42Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T17:57:42Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2013</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0971-3441</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3434</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.indianjournals.com/ijor.aspx?target=ijor:aerr&amp;volume=26&amp;issue=2&amp;article=009</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Pakistan</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1168579</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Pakistan</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1168579</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Pakistan</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1168579</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3434</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3434</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:36Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>