<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Indigenous legumes biomass quality and influence on C and N mineralization under indigenous legume fallow systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nezomba, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tauro, T.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mtambanengwe, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mapfumo, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Indigenous legumes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>N mineralization</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>lignin</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Smallholder</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>indigenous legume fallow (Indifallow)</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Phosphorus</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Non-cultivated N2-fixing indigenous legumes can be harnessed to enhance soil fertility replenishment of smallholder farms. Understanding N release patterns of biomass generated by such legumes is key in managing N availability to crops. Nitrogen and C mineralization patterns of indigenous legume species, mainly ofTephrosia andCrotalaria genera, and of soils sampled at termination of 1- and 2-year indigenous legume fallows (indifallows)were investigated in leaching tube incubations under laboratory conditions. With the exception ofTephrosia longipes Meisn (2.4%) andCrotalaria cylindrostachys Welw.ex Baker (1.8%), all indigenous legumes had &gt;2.5% N. Total polyphenols and lignin were &lt;4% and 15%, respectively, for all species.Crotalaria pallida (L.) andEriosema ellipticum Welw.ex Baker mineralized &gt;50% of the added N in the first 30 days of incubation. Similar to mixed plant biomass from natural weed fallow,C. Cylindrostachys immobilized N during the 155-day incubation period. Indifallow fallow biomass reached peak N mineralization 55 days after most legumes had leveled off. Carbon release by legume species closely followedN release patterns,with mostCrotalaria species releasing &gt;500 mg CO2-C kg&amp;#8722;1 soil. Soils sampled at termination of fallows reached peak N mineralization in the first 21 days of incubation, with indifallows mineralizing significantly (P&lt;0.05) more N than natural fallows. Application of mineral P fertilizer to indifallows and natural fallows increased C and N mineralization relative to control treatments. It was concluded that (i) indigenous legumes generate biomass of high quality within a single growing season, (ii) the slow N release of biomass generated under indifallow systems suggests that such fallows can potentially be manipulated to enhance N availability to crops, and (iii) N and C mineralization of organic materials in sandy soils is likely controlled by availability of P to the soil microbial pool.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-05T15:45:40Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-05T15:45:40Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2009</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1532</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>Englilsh</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1532</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1532</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:38Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>