<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Energy scenario, carbon efficiency, nitrogen and phosphorus dynamics of pearlmillet mustard system under diverse nutrient and tillage management practices</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Parihar, C.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bhakar, R.N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rana, K.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jat, M.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, A.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jat, S.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Parihar, M.D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sharma, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Carbon efficiency</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>consumptive use</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>energy output</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>pearlmillet-mustard system</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>N and P balance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil fertility</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Under limited moisture conditions integrated nutrient management and conservation agriculture (CA) practices plays a vital role. Information on effect of integrated nutrient management (INM) with CA practices in pearlmillet (Pennisetum glaucum) ?mustard (Brassica juncea) system is lacking.  The present experiment was conducted during 2005-06 and 2006-07 in rainy and winter seasons, at IARI, New Delhi, India to investigate the effect of INM and tillage on pearlmillet -mustard system under limited irrigation. Ridge and furrow (RF) sowing produced significantly higher carbon efficiency (CE), energy output, net returns and economic yield (3768 kg ha-1) of pearlmillet-mustard sequence. The application of 30 kg N + 30 kg P2O5 + FYM at 6 t/ha to pearlmillet produced significantly higher yield attributes, economic yield (3982 kg ha-1), energy output (194023 MJ ha-1) of the system and CE and net return (189.41 and 315.8 US$ ha-1) of pearlmillet and mustard individually over control, 30 kg N + 20 kg P2O5/ha and sole application of FYM at 6 t/ha. Direct application of 60 kg N + 40 kg P2O5/ha to mustard produced significantly higher yield attributes, economic yield (3692 kg ha-1), energy output (182097 MJ), net return (296.73 US$ ha-1) and CE (10.80 and 11.51 during both the years), over control and 30 kg N + 20 kg P2O5/ha. The application of INM with ridge furrow sowing increased available N and P contents in the soil. Whereas, the consumptive use, moisture use rates and moisture use efficiency were the highest under ridge furrow sowing of pearlmillet-mustard system.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T17:57:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T17:57:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2013</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1991-637X</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3432</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/25EA8AA35961</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>India</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1269750</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3432</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3432</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:36Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>