<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Agricultural Systems: special issue "Biomass use trade-offs in cereal cropping systems: Lessons and implications from the developing world"</dc:title>
  <dc:contributor>Erenstein, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gerard, B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tittonell, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:description>Special issue edited by Olaf Erenstein, Bruno Gérard and Pablo Tittonell.</dc:description>
  <dc:description>Table of content&#xD;
&#xD;
1.	Biomass use trade-offs in cereal cropping systems in the developing world: Overview. Olaf Erenstein, Bruno Gérard, Pablo Tittonell., p. 1-5.&#xD;
&#xD;
2.	Crop residue management and soil health: A systems analysis. Marie-Soleil Turmel, Alicia Speratti, Frédéric Baudron, Nele Verhulst, Bram Govaerts., p. 6-16.&#xD;
&#xD;
3.	Determinants of maize stover utilization as feed, fuel and soil amendment in mixed crop-livestock systems, Ethiopia. Moti Jaleta, Menale Kassie, Olaf Erenstein., p. 17-23.&#xD;
&#xD;
4.	Feeding, crop residue and manure management for integrated soil fertility management – A case study from Kenya. A. Castellanos-Navarrete, P. Tittonell, M.C. Rufino, K.E. Giller., p. 24-35.&#xD;
&#xD;
5.	Trade-offs around the use of biomass for livestock feed and soil cover in dairy farms in the Alaotra lake region of Madagascar. K. Naudin, G. Bruelle, P. Salgado, E. Penot, E. Scopel, M. Lubbers, N. de Ridder, K.E. Giller., p. 36-47.&#xD;
&#xD;
6.	Economic trade-offs of biomass use in crop-livestock systems: Exploring more sustainable options in semi-arid Zimbabwe. Sabine Homann-Kee Tui, Diego Valbuena, Patricia Masikati, Katrien Descheemaeker, Justice Nyamangara, Lieven Claessens, Olaf Erenstein, Andre van Rooyen, Daniel Nkomboni., p. 46-60.&#xD;
&#xD;
7.	Social and income trade-offs of conservation agriculture practices on crop residue use in Mexico’s central highlands. Tina D. Beuchelt, Carolina T. Camacho Villa, Lutz Göhring, Víctor M. Hernández Rodríguez, Jon Hellin, Kai Sonder, Olaf Erenstein., p. 61-75.&#xD;
&#xD;
8.	Property rights enforcement and no-till adoption in crop-livestock systems. Nicholas Magnan., p. 76-83.&#xD;
&#xD;
9.	From farm scale synergies to village scale trade-offs: Cereal crop residues use in an agro-pastoral system of the Sudanian zone of Burkina Faso.  N. Andrieu, J. Vayssières, M. Corbeels, M. Blanchard, E. Vall, P. Tittonell., p. 84-96.&#xD;
&#xD;
10.	Multi-scale trade-off analysis of cereal residue use for livestock feeding vs. soil mulching in the Mid-Zambezi Valley, Zimbabwe. Frédéric Baudron, Sylvestre Delmotte, Marc Corbeels, Juan M. Herrera, Pablo Tittonell., p. 97-106.&#xD;
&#xD;
11.	Identifying determinants, pressures and trade-offs of crop residue use in mixed smallholder farms in Sub-Saharan Africa and South Asia. Diego Valbuena, Sabine Homann-Kee Tui, Olaf Erenstein, Nils Teufel, Alan Duncan, Tahirou Abdoulaye, Braja Swain, Kindu Mekonnen, Ibro Germaine, Bruno Gérard., p. 107-118.&#xD;
&#xD;
12.	Tradeoffs around crop residue biomass in smallholder crop-livestock systems – What’s next?. Pablo Tittonell, Bruno Gérard, Olaf Erenstein., p. 119-128.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-04-09T22:00:19Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2015-04-09T22:00:19Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2015</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:issn>0308-521X</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/4241</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Africa</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255146</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>4241</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_4241</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:45Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>