<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Isolation, fine mapping and expression profiling of a lesion mimic genotype, splNF4050-8 that confers blast resistance in rice</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Babu, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chang-Jie Jiang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xin Xu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kameswara Rao Kottapalli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hiroshi Takatsuji</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Akio Miyao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hirohiko Hirochika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shinji Kawasaki</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>We evaluated a large collection of Tos17 mutant panel lines for their reaction to three different races of Magnaporthe oryzae and identified a lesion mimic mutant, NF4050-8, that showed lesions similar to naturally occurring spl5 mutant and enhanced resistance to all the three blast races tested. Nested modified-AFLP using Tos17-specific primers and southern hybridization experiments of segregating individuals indicated that the lesion mimic phenotype in NF4050-8 is most likely due to a nucleotide change acquired during the culturing process and not due to Tos17 insertion per se. Inheritance and genetic analyses in two japonica × indica populations identified an overlapping genomic region of 13 cM on short arm of chromosome 7 that was linked with the lesion mimic phenotype. High-resolution genetic mapping using 950 F3 and 3,821 F4 plants of NF4050-8 × CO39 delimited a 35 kb region flanked by NBARC1 (5.262 Mb) and RM8262 (5.297 Mb), which contained 6 ORFs; 3 of them were ?resistance gene related? with typical NBS?LRR signatures. One of them harbored a NB?ARC domain, which had been previously demonstrated to be associated with cell death in animals. Microarray analysis of NF4050-8 revealed significant up-regulation of numerous defense/pathogenesis-related genes and down-regulation of heme peroxidase genes. Real-time PCR analysis of WRKY45 and PR1b genes suggested possible constitutive activation of a defense signaling pathway downstream of salicylic acid but independent of NH1 in these mutant lines of rice.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:43Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:43Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2011</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0040-5752</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1818</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1818</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1818</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:46Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>