<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Preferences and constraints of maize farmers in the development and adoption of improved varieties in the mid-altitude, sub-humid agro-ecology of Western Ethiopia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Abera, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hussein, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Derera, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Worku, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laing, M.D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farmers' constraints</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>production packages</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zea mays</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Understanding farmers' production constraints and preferences is important in maize breeding, especially underlying successful adoption of improved varieties and their production packages. This study was conducted to assess the present importance, and productivity constraints of maize in the mid-altitude, sub-humid agro-ecology of Western Ethiopia. Data was collected through a semi-structured questionnaire and focus group discussions, using 240 randomly selected respondent farmers, in 12 sub-districts, within three administrative zones. Maize was ranked number one as both food and cash crop by 82.9% of respondents. Most farmers (59%) use hybrids, while 24% grow landrace varieties. Unavailability of improved seed and lack of production inputs were the two major constraints reducing maize productivity, as reported by 62 and 60% of respondents, respectively. A high proportion of respondents (80%) indicated that, unpredictable grain prices are the major market constraint as 97% of the respondents sell their maize crop in the local market. Northern corn leaf blight (NCLB) was reported to be important by 46% of respondents. Breeding for improved disease resistance and grain yield, enhancing the availability of crop input and stabilizing market price during harvest time are the most important strategies to increase maize production by small-scale farmers in Western Ethiopia.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11-24T18:23:49Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-11-24T18:23:49Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2013</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1991-637X</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3265</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.academicjournals.org/ajar/abstracts/abstracts/Abstracts%202013/18Apr/Abera%20et%20al.htm</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Ethiopia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/337996</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3265</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3265</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:50Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>