<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Heat and drought stress on durum wheat: Responses of genotypes, yield, and quality parameters</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yun-Fang Li</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yu Wu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hernandez-Espinosa, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peña-Bautista, R.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Drought and heat stress</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Durum wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Flour yellowness</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>gluten strength</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Heat and/or drought stress during cultivation are likely to affect the processing quality of durum wheat (Triticum turgidum L. ssp. durum). This work examined the effects of drought and heat stress conditions on grain yield and quality parameters of nine durum wheat varieties, grown during two years (2008?09 and 2009?10). Generally, G and E showed main effects on all the parameters whereas the effects of G × E were relatively small. More precipitation in Y09?10 may account for the large differences in parameters observed between crop cycles (Y08?09 and Y09?10). Combined results of the two crop cycles showed that flour protein content (FP) and SDS sedimentation volume (SDSS) increased under both stress conditions, but not significantly. In contrast the gluten strength-related parameters lactic acid retention capacity (LARC) and mixograph peak time (MPT) increased and decreased significantly under drought and heat stress, respectively. Drought and heat stress drastically reduced grain yield (Y) but significantly enhanced flour yellowness (FY). LARC and the swelling index of glutenin (SIG) could be alternative tests to screen for gluten strength. Genotypes and qualtiy parameters performed differently to drought and heat stress, which justifies screening durum wheat for both yield and quality traits under these two abiotic stress conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11-25T02:37:38Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-11-25T02:37:38Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2013</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0733-5210</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3287</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0733521013000118</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3287</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3287</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:09Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>