<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Simulation Experiments on efficiencies of gene introgression by backcrossing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ribaut, J.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jiang, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hoisington, D.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Plant breeding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genomes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genotypes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nucleotides</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Introgression</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>DNA</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Designing a highly efficient backcross (BC) marker-assisted selection (MAS) experiment is not a straightforward exercise, efficiency being defined here as the ratio between the resources that need to be invested at each generation and the number of generations required to achieve the selection. This paper presents results of simulations conducted for different strategies, using the maize genome as a model, to compare allelic introgression with DNA markers through BCs. Simulation results indicate that the selection response in the BCl could be increased significantly when the selectable population size (N sl) is &lt;50, and that a diminished return is observed when this number &gt;100. Selectable population size is defined as the number of individuals with favorable alleles at the target loci from which selection with markers can be carried out on the rest of the genome at nontarget loci, simulations considered the allelic introgression at one to five target loci, with different population sizes, changes in the recombination frequency between target loci and nanking markers, and different numbers of genotypes selected at each generation. For an introgression at one target locus in a partial line conversion, and using MAS at nontarget loci only at one generation, a selection at BC, would be more efficient than a selection at BC, or BC" due to the increase over generations of the ratio of the standard deviation to the mean of the donor genome contribution. With selection only for the presence of a donor allele at one locus in BC, and BC" and MAS at BC" lines with &lt;5% of the donor genome can be obtained with a N sl,of 10 inBC, and BC" and 100 in BC,. These results are critical in the application of molecular markers to introgress elite alleles as part of plant improvement programs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:07:50Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:07:50Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2002</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1947</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1947</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1947</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:45Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>