<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Characterization of Yr54 and other genes associated with adult plant resistance to yellow rust and leaf rust in common wheat Quaiu 3</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Basnet, B.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, R.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ibrahim, A.M.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Herrera-Foessel, S.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huerta-Espino, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caixia Lan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rudd, J.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>RILs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markers</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>QTL</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>APR</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Yellow rust</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Leaf rust (LR) and yellow rust (YR), caused by Puccinia triticina and Puccinia striiformis f. sp. tritici, respectively, are important diseases of wheat. Quaiu 3, a common wheat line developed at the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT), is immune to YR in Mexico despite seedling susceptibility to predominant races. Quaiu 3 also shows immunity to LR in field trials and is known to possess the race-specific gene Lr42. A mapping population of 182 recombinant inbred lines (RILs) was developed by crossing Quaiu 3 with susceptible Avocet-YrA and phenotyped with LR and YR in field trials for 2 years in Mexico. Quantitative trait loci (QTL) associated with YR and LR resistance in the RILs were identified using Diversity Arrays Technology and simple sequence repeat markers. A large-effect QTL on the long arm of chromosome 2D explained 49?54 % of the phenotypic variation in Quaiu 3 and was designated as Yr54. Two additional loci on 1BL and 3BS explained 8?17 % of the phenotypic variation for YR and coincided with previously characterized adult plant resistance (APR) genes Lr46/Yr29 and Sr2/Yr30, respectively. QTL on 1DS and 1BL corresponding to Lr42 and Lr46/Yr29, respectively, contributed 60?71 % of the variation for LR resistance. A locus on 3D associated with APR to both diseases explained up to 7 % of the phenotypic variance. Additional Avocet-YrA-derived minor QTL were also detected for YR on chromosomes 1A, 3D, 4A, and 6A. Yr54 is a newly characterized APR gene which can be combined with other genes by using closely linked molecular markers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T18:04:36Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T18:04:36Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2014</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1380-3743</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3476</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11032-013-9957-2</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Mexico</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3996063</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3476</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3476</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:10Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>