<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of insect population density and storage time on grain damage and weight loss in maize due to the maize weevil Sitophilus zeamais and the larger grain borer Prostephanus truncatus</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tadele Tefera</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mugo, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Likhayo, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>soybean</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>weed seedbank</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Amaranthus retroflexus L.</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Chenopodium album L.</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Datura stramonium L.</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the period 2007 to 2010, at localities Backi Maglic and Krivaja studies of weed seedbank were performed under soybean crop. Results showed that weed seed separated at Backi Maglic in all years dominated in the top soil layer, while the lowest quantities were separated from the deepest layer, and that number of weeds declined annually. At Krivaja, the lowest weed seed stocks were found in the top layer, and the highest in the deepest layer. At this locality, number of weed seeds kept rising from season to season, which was the consequence of application of different cultural practices.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-30T05:24:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-30T05:24:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2011</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1991-637X</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3130</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3130</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3130</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:52Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>