<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of the 6VS.6AL translocation on agronomic traits and dough properties of wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Guiping Li</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peidu Chen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shouzhong Zhang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiue Wang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yan Zhang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huiyao Huang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiangchun Zhou</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Grain yield</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pm21</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>powdery mildew</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Triticum aestivum L</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wide crosses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nineteen common wheat cultivars and advanced lines carrying a 6VS.6AL translocation and five parents were sown at two locations in Jiangsu in 2004&amp;ndash;05 season to assess the effects of the translocation on grain yield and dough properties. In general, there were no significant differences between 6VS.6AL lines and their recurrent parents in agronomic, mixograph and starch pasting traits, including grain yield, grains/spike, grain weight/spike, mixing time and peak viscosity. 6VS.6AL lines showed slightly but significantly higher thousand-kernel weight and plant height, and small negative effects on test weight, flour yield and flour colour. However, significant variation occurred for all traits among sister lines from the same cross, indicating that additional selection could lead to further improvement. It was concluded that the 6VS.6AL translocation can be used in wheat breeding programs as a donor of resistance to powdery mildew with no obvious undesirable effects on agronomic and quality traits.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:08Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:08Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2007</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2605</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2605</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2605</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:11Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>