<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Factors explaining the diffusion of hybrid maize in Latin America and the Caribbean region</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kosarek, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garcia, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morris, M.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Latin America</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Caribbean</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zea mays</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Varieties</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hybrids</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Life cycle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Seed industry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Innovation adoption</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Input output analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Development policies</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>If future demand for maize in Latin America and the Caribbean region (LAC) is to be met from local sources, domestic production must continue to increase. Because further expansion in the area planted to maize is precluded by the limited availability of arable land, future increases in production will have to rely heavily on the spread of productivity-enhancing hybrid technology. Until now, the diffusion of hybrid maize in LAC has been quite variable. Using data from 18 countries, we investigate factors affecting the hybrid maize diffusion rate. Our findings validate conventional profitability-based explanations of producer adoption behavior, but they also confirm the importance of supply-side factors, thereby providing empirical support for the life cycle theory of seed industry development. We conclude that if policy makers in LAC are to accelerate the diffusion of hybrid maize, they will have to ensure an environment in which it is not only profitable for producers to adopt improved germplasm, but also profitable for the seed industry to produce and sell high-quality seed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:07:53Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:07:53Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2001</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1967</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1967</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1967</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:47Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>