<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of terminal heat stress on yield and yield components of spring bread wheat cultivars in Ahwaz, Iran</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moshatati, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Siadat, S.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alami Saeid, Kh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bakhshandeh, A.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jalal Kamali, M.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Terminal heat stress</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sowing date</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cultivars</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Grain yield</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In order to study the effect of terminal heat stress on grain yield and yield components of spring bread wheat cultivars, a stripe block design was conducted using randomized complete block design with three replications in 35 Km north-east Ahwaz in 2007-2008 cropping season. The vertical plots included four sowing dates (06 Nov., 06 Dec., 05 Jan. and 04 Feb.) and 20 cultivars (Atrak, Arvand1, S-80-18, Star, Inia66, Bolani, Bayat, Pishtaz, Chamran, Chenab70, Darab, Dez, Roshan, Shoeleh, Kavir, Maroon, Hamoon, Hirman and Vee/Nac) were randomized in horizontal plots. The results showed that sowing date, cultivars and their interaction had significant effects on all measured traits. The highest grain yield (5.949 t/ha) was produced in sowing dates of 06 Dec. and the lowest grain yield (1.690 t/ha) was produced in sowing dates of 04 Feb. Chamran had the highest grain yield and Inia66 had the lowest grain yield. Maximum grain yield (7.039 t/ha) related to Chamran in 06 Dec. and the minimum grain yield (1.219 t/ha) belonged to Falat in 04 Feb.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11-25T02:37:43Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-11-25T02:37:43Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2012</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>2228-7973</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3310</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:pdf>http://ecisi.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/844-849.doc.pdf</dc:pdf>
  <dc:geotag>Iran</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/130758</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3310</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3310</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:10Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>