<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Allelic variation of glutenin, granule-bound starch synthase I and puroindoline in Korean wheat cultivar</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chul Soo Park</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peña-Bautista, R.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Byung-Kee Baik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>chon-Sik Kang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hwa-Young Heo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Young-keun Cheong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sun-Hee Woo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>high-molecular-weight glutenin subunits</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>(HMW-GS)</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>(LMW-GS)</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>granule-bound starch synthase I</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>(GBSSI)</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>puroindoline</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To investigate the genetic variation of highand low-molecular-weight glutenin subunits (HMW-GS and LMW-GS), granule-bound starch synthase I (GBSSI) and puroindoline in 24 Korean wheat cultivars. At the HMW-GS compositions, three Glu-A1 alleles, five Glu-B1 alleles and three Glu-D1 alleles were identified. The high frequency of alleles at each locus was Glu-A1c allele (15 cultivars), Glu-B1b allele (16 cultivars) and Glu-D1f allele (16 cultivars). Four alleles were identified at the Glu-A3 and Glu-B3 loci and three at Glu-D3 locus and Glu-A3d, Glu-B3d and Glu-D3a were mainly found at each Glu-3 locus. Glu-A3d, Glu-B3d, Glu-D3b or c (4 cultivars, respectively) and Glu-A3d, Glu-B3d, Glu-D3a and Glu-A3c, Glu-B3d or h, Glu-D3a (3 cultivar, respectively) were predominantly found in Korean wheats. At the GBSS compositions, 2 waxy wheat cultivars, Shinmichal and Shinmichal1, showed null alleles on the Wx loci and other cultivars were wild type in GBSS compositions. At the puroindoline gene compositions, Korean wheat cultivars carried 3 genotypes, which 10 cultivars (41.7%) were Pina-D1a and Pinb-D1a, 11 cultivars (45.8%) had Pina-D1a and Pinb-D1b and 3 cultivars (12.5%) carried Pina-D1b and Pinb-D1a. These genetic variations could present the information to improve flour and end-use quality in Korean wheat breeding programs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:31Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:31Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2009</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2744</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2744</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2744</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:06Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>