<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Assessment of the nitrogen management strategy using an optical sensor for irrigated wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bijay-Singh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sharma, R.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jaspreet-Kaur</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jat, M.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martin, K.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yadvinder-Singh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Varinderpal-Singh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chandna, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Choudhary, O.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gupta, R.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thind, H.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jagmohan-Singh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Uppal, H.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Khurana, H.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kumar, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Uppal, R.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vashistha, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raun, W.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gupta, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Indo-Gangetic Plain</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Irrigated wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nitrogen management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Response index</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>GreenSeeker optical sensor</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Potential yield</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Blanket fertilizer nitrogen (N) recommendations for large irrigated wheat tracts lead to low N-use efficiency due to field-to-field variability in soil N supply and seasonal variability in yield. To achieve high N use efficiency, a site-specific N management strategy using GreenSeeker? optical sensor was evaluated. We conducted seven field experiments during 2004?2006 at three locations to define relationships between in-season sensor measurements and yield of wheat and to know whether response of wheat to fertilizer N can be estimated by sensor measurements. During 2005?2007, four field experiments were conducted to assess the sensor-based N management strategy and to work out prescriptive N management to be followed prior to applying sensor-guided fertilizer dose. We observed robust relationships between in-season sensor-based estimates of yield at Feekes 5?6 and 7?8 stages and actual wheat yields. Response of wheat to fertilizer N defined by the sensor was highly correlated with harvest response index. Sensor-guided fertilizer N applications resulted in high yield levels and high N-use efficiency. Application of 90 kg N ha-1 at planting or in two equal doses at planting and crown root initiation stage was the appropriate prescriptive fertilizer N management. This study reveals that high N-use efficiency in irrigated wheat can be achieved by replacing blanket fertilizer recommendation by an optical sensor-based N management strategy consisting of applying moderate amount of fertilizer N at planting and crown root initiation stages and sensor-guided fertilizer N dose at Feekes 5?6 or 7?8 stages of wheat.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-05T15:45:43Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-05T15:45:43Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2011</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1774-0746</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1553</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1553</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1553</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:38Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>