<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of single cross quality protein maize (QPM) hybrids for kernel iron and zinc concentrations</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chakraborti, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prasanna, B.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hossain, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, A.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biofortification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kernel micronutrient</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Iron</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zinc</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>QPM</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study was carried out to ascertain the potential of Quality Protein Maize (QPM) genotypes for attaining desirable kernel iron (Fe) and zinc (Zn) concentrations. Forty two QPM hybrids generated out of seven inbreds varied significantly for kernel Fe and Zn concentrations, and grain yield at both Hyderabad and Delhi locations during 2007?2008. Considering both the micronutrient traits, DQPM-3 × DQPM-2 (Fe=38.46 mg/kg; Zn=39.92 mg/kg) at Hyderabad; and DQPM-7 × DQPM-3 (Fe=30.06 mg/kg; Zn=30.69 mg/kg) at Delhi were identified as the most promising cross combinations. Reciprocal effects for both the micronutrient traits were observed in some of the cross combination. The study revealed the influence of environment in determining the kernel micronutrient traits. Despite the presence of 'dilution effect', superior QPM hybrids with enriched kernel Fe and Zn concentrations were identified in the study. Kernel Fe and Zn concentrations were positively correlated, while no significant associations were found between either of the micronutrients with grain yield, suggesting the possibility of simultaneous improvement of both the kernel micronutrients without negatively impacting grain yield in the QPM hybrids.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-30T05:24:46Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-30T05:24:46Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2011</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3170</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.indianjournals.com/ijor.aspx?target=ijor:ijgpb&amp;volume=71&amp;issue=4&amp;article=003</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3170</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3170</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:52Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>