<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wheat grain yield and stability assessed through regional trials in the eastern Gangetic plains of South Asia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sharma, R.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ortiz-Ferrara, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crossa, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bhatta, M.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sufian, M.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shoran, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Joshi, A.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chand, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ortiz, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Grain yield</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Improvement</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Stability</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Triticum aestivum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Bread wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Improving the level and stability of grain yield is the primary objective of wheat breeding programs in the Eastern Gangetic Plains (EGP) of South Asia. A regional wheat trial, the Eastern Gangetic Plains Yield Trial (EGPYT), was initiated by CIMMYT in collaboration with national wheat research programs in Bangladesh, Nepal, and India in 1999&amp;ndash;2000 to identify wheat genotypes with high and stable grain yield, disease resistance, and superior agronomic traits for the EGP region. A set of 21 wheat experimental genotypes selected from a regional wheat screening nursery in South Asia, three improved widely grown cultivars (Kanchan, PBW343 and Bhrikuti), and one long-term cultivar (Sonalika) were tested at 9&amp;ndash;11 sites in six wheat growing seasons (2000&amp;ndash;2005) in the EGP. The 21 experimental genotypes were different in each year, whereas the four check cultivars were common. In each year, one or more of the experimental genotypes showed high and stable grain yield and acceptable maturity, plant height, and disease resistance compared to the check cultivars. Three improved cultivars have already been commercially released in the region through EGPYT and many germplasm lines have been used in the breeding programs as parents. Identification of wheat genotypes with high-grain yield in individual sites and high and stable yield across the EGP region underlines their value for regional wheat breeding programs attempting to improve grain yield and agronomic performance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:05Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:05Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2007</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2586</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Bangladesh</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1210997</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Nepal</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1282988</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>India</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1269750</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2586</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2586</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:11Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>