<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Heterodera avenae yumurtalarinin inkubasyonu uzerine sicakligin etkisi ile en uygun deneme yontem ve materyallerinin arastirilmasi</dc:title>
  <dc:title>Effect of temperatures on incubation duration of Heterodera avenae cysts and optimization of some materials and methods</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Imren, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Toktay, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ozarslandan, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dababat, A.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Elekcioglu, I.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereal cyst nematodes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hatching</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Life cycle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study, the effect of temperatures on the incubation duration of the cereal cyst nematode cysts, Heterodera avenae (Wollenweber, 1924) and determining of the optimum methods and materials was investigated under in-vitro conditions. The effect of tempratures on incubation duration of Heterodera avenae cysts was studied on two different incubation stages. First incubation exposured to all cysts was set up 66 days at 4ºC after each samples transfered different temperatures (5, 10, 15, 20 and 25ºC). The cumulative hatching percent was significantly effected by different temperatures at the end of 252 days. Hatching was greater at lower temperatures (5, 10 15 ºC) compared to at higher temperatures of (20, 25ºC) ranging between 46.7, 82.3 and 45.9 % vs and 30.7 and 19.0%, respectively. Although the highest cumulative hatching of 82.3% was obtained at a constant 10ºC at 252 days, the lowest cumulative hatching of 19.0% was obtained to 25ºC at 252 days. The most suitable soil type for the in-vitro conditions was found the sandy soil (70 % sand: 29% field soil: 1% organic matter), best inoculation rate was 2,5 second stage juveniles  per gram soil and inoculation time at planting day.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:57Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:57Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2012</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1010-6960</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2941</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>tur</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2941</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2941</dc:apiid>
  <dc:lexvo>http://lexvo.org/id/iso639-3/tur</dc:lexvo>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:09Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>