<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A diagnostic study of crop-livestock interactions : in the Rift Valley and the western mid-highland areas of Ethiopia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tolemariam, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jaleta Debello Moti</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Livestock</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report analyzes crop-livestock interactions in maize-based, mixed farming systems in the Rift Valley and the&#xD;
western, mid-highland areas of Ethiopia. These areas are known for their maize-based crop-livestock farming&#xD;
systems. Cross sectional survey data collected from 300 households in the Rift Valley area and among 199&#xD;
households in the western, mid-highlands were used for the analysis. The results show that there is a strong&#xD;
interaction between crop and livestock production at the household level. Crop residue produced from major&#xD;
cereal crops is used as livestock feed. Compared to other cattle types, households keep relatively larger numbers&#xD;
of oxen, which are the only sources of draft power in crop production. Manure used in cereal crop production,&#xD;
mainly for maize, comes from livestock. Generally, existing trends indicate a strong complementarity between&#xD;
crop and livestock production at the household level.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-10-27T22:07:36Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2015-10-27T22:07:36Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2015</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/4581</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Ethiopia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/337996</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>4581</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_4581</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:45Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>