<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Linking global and local approaches to agricultural technology development: the role of participatory plant breeding research in the CGIAR</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bellon, M.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morris, M.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Economic policies</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plant breeding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research institutions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germplasm</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research projects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>CGIAR</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Agricultural development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Innovation adoption</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Appropriate technology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Agricultural policies</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper describes the current state of international plant breeding research and explains why centralized approach to germplasm improvement, so successful in the past, is being transformed by decentralized local breeding methods that incorporate the perspective of end users in varietal development. The paper examines international breeding efforts for major crops and identifies factors that contributed to its success, describes shortcomings of the global approach to plant breeding, and explains why future successes will depend on researchers&amp;rsquo; ability to incorporate the knowledge and preferences of technology users. The paper then reviews a number of participatory research methods that are currently being tested in the developing world and highlights a range of approaches in different settings and with different crops. Finally, the paper discusses potential synergies that can be achieved by linking centralized and decentralized global methods and the technical, economic, and institutional challenges that have to be overcome to integrate end-user based participatory approaches into the international plant breeding system.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:07:29Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:07:29Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2002</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0258-8587</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/912</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:relation>CIMMYT Economics Working Paper</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>912</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_912</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:52Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>