<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Variation in partial resistance to barley leaf rust ( Puccinia hordei) and agronomic characters of Ethiopian landrace lines</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Woldeab, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fininsa, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yuen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crossa, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Barley</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Barley landraces</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hordeum vulgare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Leaf rust/brown rust</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Puccinia hordei</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Partial resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An inventory of 481 lines derived from 12 Ethiopian barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) landraces and the checks was made for partial resistance to Puccinia hordei under greenhouse and field conditions at Adet, Ambo and Sinana Agricultural Research Centers in 2003 and 2004 cropping seasons in Ethiopia. The experiments were laid out in a triple lattice design. Each plot consisted of two rows of 1&amp;ndash;m long with spacing of 0.20 m between rows. The overall mean leaf rust epidemics varied from area under disease progress curve (AUDPC) of 86 to 1,835. The disease was as high as AUDPC 1,378 on the susceptible check L94. Highly significant variations were recorded between and within the landraces/lines in leaf rust incidence, severity, days to heading, plant height, thousand seed weight and yield. Similarly, the variations between and within barley groups from three altitude areas and three ear-types were significant. Landraces 1686, 3255, 3262 and 3783 had the least and landraces 219900, 3975 and 3980 had the highest leaf rust severity. Of the 481 lines tested, 413 (86%) had significantly lower disease than the susceptible check, but not than the partial resistant check Vada. In contrast, the yields were more for lines with less disease than for those with high. The frequency of resistant landraces/lines was more in altitude 2,301&amp;ndash;2,500 m, and irregular and two rows ear-types than in lower altitude areas and six rows ear-type. Nevertheless, the correlation and regression analysis revealed the adverse effect of the disease in the yields of barley. The 413 lines with high infection types at seedling stage and lower AUDPC under field conditions possess partial resistance to leaf rust.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:07Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:07Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2007</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2598</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2598</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2598</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:11Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>