<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Characterization of Lr34/Yr18, Rht-B1b, Rht-D1b genes in CIMMYT wheat cultivars and advanced lines using STS markers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Liang Dan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yang Fang-Ping</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yao Da-Nian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xia Xian-chun</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Triticum aestivum L.</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>slow rusting resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>dwarfing gene</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>molecular marker</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>(Objective) Characterization of genes Lr34/Yr18, Rht-B1b (Rht1) and Rht-D1b (Rht2) in 263 CIMMYT wheat cultivars and advanced lines will benefit the improvement of rust resistance and plant height in Chinese wheat breeding program.  (Method) A total of 263 CIMMYT wheat cultivars and advanced lines were tested by STS markers to understand the distribution of resistance genes Lr34/Yr18 and dwarfing genes Rht-B1b and Rht-D1b. (Result) The marker csLV34 could amplify a 150 bp fragment in the lines with Lr34/Yr18, and a 229 bp fragment in those lines without Lr34/Yr18. Two complementary markers, NH-BF.2/WR1.2 and NH-BF.2/MR1, were used to investigate the alleles Rht-B1a and Rht-B1b, respectively. They could amplify a 400 bp fragment in the genotypes with Rht-B1a and Rht-B1b, respectively. The marker DF/MR2 could generate a 280 bp fragment in the genotype with Rht-D1b. Of the 263 lines, 57 generated a 150 bp fragment with the marker csLV34, indicating the presence of Lr34/Yr18 in these lines, with a frequency of 21.7%. Two hundred and sixteen lines (82.1%) were detected to have the allele Rht-B1b and 38 lines (14.4%) contained the allele Rht-D1b. Twenty-one lines were detected to possess both the wild-type alleles Rht-B1a and Rht-D1a, while 12 had two dwarfing genes Rht-B1b and Rht-D1b. (Conclusion) These STS markers could be useful to detect the genes Lr34/Yr18, Rht-B1b and Rht-D1b. The frequency of Rht-B1b was much higher than that of Rht-D1b in CIMMYT lines.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:30Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:30Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2009</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2737</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>zho</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://211.155.251.135:81/Jwk_zgnykx/EN/abstract/abstract9874.shtml</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2737</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2737</dc:apiid>
  <dc:lexvo>http://lexvo.org/id/iso639-3/zho</dc:lexvo>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:06Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>