<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Economics of nitrogen fertiliser application in rice, wheat and maize grown in the indo-gangetic plains</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Satyanarayana, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Majumdar, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shahi, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kumar, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pampolino, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jat, M.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, V.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gupta, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dwivedi, B.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kumar, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Malik, R.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sidhu, H.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Johnston, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>Nitrogen (N) is a key factor for cereal production in India. N is predominantly supplied to the plants through fertiliser application. The average response to applied fertiliser N has been declining steadily over the past decades. As a result, farmers are compelled to apply higher doses of fertiliser N to maintain the yields of the preceding years. Considering the increasing demand of N fertiliser in the coming years, wide variability in soil N supplying capacity and wide production gaps in the predominant cereals, the present on-farm study was undertaken in the Indo-Gangetic Plains (IGP). The objective was to estimate response of cereals (rice, wheat and maize) to N application, the economics and profitability of N application with changing fertiliser price scenario.  On-farm results indicated yield loss due to N omission to the tune of 667-3337 kg ha-1in rice, 500-4750 kg ha-1 in wheat and 400- 5160 kg ha-1 in maize. On the other hand, optimum use of N at observed N response levels, current and projected prices of N fertiliser and minimum support price of rice, wheat and maize had return on investment e? 3 indicating increasing significance of precise N management in cereals in the IGP. Results also suggest that advanced strategies of N management considering the indigenous N supplying capacity of soil, yield response, and agronomic efficiency of N at a given environment may become an important tool for improving farm profitability from N use in IGP.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T20:59:20Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T20:59:20Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2012</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>No</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1590</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1590</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1590</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:38Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>