<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Polimorphism of high molecular weight glutenins and its relationship with in rainfed bread wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:title>| Polimorfismo de gluteninas de alto peso molecular y su relación con trigos harineros para temporal</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Espitia Rangel, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martinez Cruz, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peña Bautista, R.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Villaseñor Mir, H.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huerta Espino, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>bread-making quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>high molecular weight glutenins</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Bread wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In order to identify the high molecular weight glutenins subunits and its relationship with the bread-making quality, as well as to characterize the bread quality of the group of genotypes of bread wheat (Triticum aestivum L.), 130 genotypes were seeded under rainfed conditions at Santa Lucia de Prias, Estado de Mexico in 2001. In the analysis of physical and chemical quality the traits considered were test weight (kg hL-1), grain hardness (%), grain and fl our protein (%) and sedimentation volume (mL). The rheological analysis was based on the basis of mixed time (min), mixogram-height (cm), Overmixing tolerance (mm), mixogram-stability (min), alveogram-W (10 -4 J), alveogram- P/L with scale from 0.1 to 6 and alveogram-P/G (scale from 1.5 to 14). In the bread-making analysis bread loaf volume (mL) and bread crumb texture (1-6 scale) were considered. The identification of high molecular weight glutenins was made by electrophoresis in SDS-Polyacrylamida (SDS-PAGE) gel. The alleles 2* and 1 of the genome A, 17+18 and 7+8 of genome B and 5+10 of genome D, showed a positive effect on the bread-making quality, allele 7+9 of genome B showed an intermediate effect and the alleles, null (0) of the genome A and 2+12 of genome D showed a negative effect, all these alleles showed the highest frequency in genotypes. The combinations most frequently found were 2*-7+9-5+10, 2*-17+18-5+10 and 1-17+18-5+10, with 28.6%, 22.7% and 12.6% respectively; the last two combinations presented the best bread volume with 867 and 883 mL, respectively.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:18Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:18Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2008</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2660</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://bit.ly/YfUeHs</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Mexico</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3996063</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2660</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2660</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:04Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>