<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Meta-analysis of constitutive and adaptive QTL for drought tolerance in maize</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zhuanfang Hao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xinhai Li</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiulin Liu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chuanxiao Xie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mingshun Li</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Degui Zhang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shihuang Zhang</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Drought</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>QTL</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The response of plants to drought stress is very complex and involves expression of a lot of genes and pathways for diverse mechanisms and interactions with environments. Many quantitative trait loci(QTL) mapping experiments have given heterogeneous results due to use of different genotypes and populations tested in various environments. Our purpose was to identify some important constitutive and adaptive QTL using meta-analysis and to find specific genes and their families for speculating on drought tolerance networks. A total of 239 QTL detected under water-stressed conditions and 160 detected under control conditions from 12 populations tested in 22 experiments were compiled and compared, resulting in identification of 39 consensus QTL under water stress, and 36 under control conditions. Of them, 32 consensus QTL were supposed to be adaptive while others were constitutive QTL. The consensus QTL on chromosomes 1, 2, 3, 5, 6 and 9 were highly overlapped with several different traits and could be identified under multiple environments, most of which were related to traits of high phenotypic variance. Moreover, 48 candidate genes related to stress tolerance were located in silico in these consensus QTL regions what should facilitate the construction of QTL networks and help to understand the mechanisms related to drought tolerance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:47Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:47Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2010</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0014-2336</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1844</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1844</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1844</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:45Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>