<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Chemical methods used at CIMMYT for determining protein quality in cereal grains</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Villegas, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ortega Martinez, E.I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bauer, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Zea mays</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Chemical analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Protein quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Triticales</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nitrogen content</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Barley</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tryptophan</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lysine</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Varieties</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Chemical methods used at the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT) for determining protein quality in cereal grains are briefly described in this bulletin. The techniques included have been used to rapidly identify and select improved cereal lines by screening early generation germplasm from the different breeding programs at CIMMYT. In addition, the use of some of these techniques may provide a more complete biochemical information in outstanding materials which have been selected after several cycles of agronomic improvement. For each method, a small introduction, a list of reagents and equipment needed as well as a</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-13T00:57:50Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2014-03-13T00:57:50Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1984</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Grey literature</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3755</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3755</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3755</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:10Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>