<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Construction of genetic linkage map and QTL analysis of sink-size traits in pearl millet (Pennisetum glaucum)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vengadessan, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rai, K.N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kannan Bapu, J.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hash, C.T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bhattacharjee, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Senthilvel, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vinayan, M.T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nepolean, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>A linkage map, primarily based on SSCP-SNP markers, was constructed using 188 F2:3 mapping population progenies produced from a cross between two pearl millet inbred lines having diverse parentage. The skeleton linkage map covered 1019&amp;#8201;cM and it comprised of 44 markers distributed across the seven linkage groups. Average adjacent-marker intervals ranged from on LG1 to  on LG6, with an overall mean of . Using the F2 linkage map and phenotypic data from the F2 and F2:3 generations of the mapping population, a total of 18 putative QTLs were detected for the three sink-size components. Eight QTLs explained 42.7% of observed phenotypic variation for panicle length using the F2:3 data set. For panicle diameter, 5 QTLs explained 45.8% of observed phenotypic variation. Similarly for grain size, 5 QTLs explained 29.6% of phenotypic variation. Genomic regions associated with panicle length, panicle diameter, and grain size were comapped on LG6 between Xpsms88 and Xpsms2270, indicating the existence of a gene or gene cluster. The QTLs for panicle length on LG2 and LG6 ( in both F2 and F2:3 data sets), for panicle diameter on LG2 and LG3 ( in the F2:3 data set), and for grain size on LG3 and LG6 ( in both F2 and F2:3 data sets) were identified as promising candidates for validation prior to possible application in marker-assisted breeding.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T17:51:03Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T17:51:03Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2013</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3413</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.hindawi.com/isrn/genetics/2013/471632/</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3413</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3413</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:50Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>