<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Segregation analysis indicates that Puroindoline b-2 variants 2 and 3 are allelic in Triticum aestivum and that a revision to Puroindoline b-2 gene symbolization is indicated</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hongwei Geng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Beecher, B.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pumphrey, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morris, C.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>kernel hardness</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Bread wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Puroindoline b-2 variants</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Segregation ratios</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Genetic and kernel texture relationships between Puroindoline b-2 variants 2 and 3 have not been fully established in wheat (Triticum aestivum L.). Here, 480 F2 plants, derived from three hard spring wheat populations were used to test the segregation of Puroindoline b-2 (Pinb-2) variants 2 and 3. Chi-square analysis indicated that Pinb-2 variants 2 and 3 in all three F2 populations segregated as a single bi-allelic locus, with segregation ratios fitting a 1:2:1 ratio. Using 448 of the 480 plants derived from these three F2 populations, the average SKCS hardness index of plants homozygous for Pinb-2 variant 2 vs. those homozygous for variant 3 was not significantly different (67.5 vs. 67.9). Results indicated that plants with Pina-D1b/Pinb-D1a were on average 10.0 Single Kernel Characterization System (SKCS) hardness index units harder than those carrying the Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1b haplotype. In conclusion, Pinb-2 variants 2 and 3 are allelic and exert little effect on kernel texture in hard-kernel T. aestivum germplasm. Further, the designation of Pinb-2v2 and Pinb-2v3 should be changed to Pinb-B2a and Pinb-B2b, respectively. We propose that Pinb-2 variants 1 and 4 of Chinese Spring be designated Pinb-D2a and Pinb-A2a, respectively.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11-25T02:37:36Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-11-25T02:37:36Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2013</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0733-5210</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3279</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0733521012002214</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3279</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3279</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:09Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>