<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Grain a day : @CIMMYT #grainaday</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Cooking</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recipes</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Globally, an estimated 800 million people do not get enough food to eat and more than 2 billion&#xD;
suffer from micronutrient deficiency, or “hidden hunger,” according to U.N. food agencies.&#xD;
As staple foods, maize and wheat provide vital nutrients and health benefits, making up close&#xD;
to two-thirds of the world’s food energy intake, and contributing 55 to 70 percent of the total&#xD;
calories in the diets of people living in developing countries, according to the U.N. Food and&#xD;
Agriculture Organization.&#xD;
Scientists at the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT) are working to&#xD;
ensure the ongoing production of high-yielding, disease-resistant varieties of maize and wheat&#xD;
to improve both the quantity and nutritional quality of these crops.&#xD;
These measures include biofortification, a process by which scientists combine conventional&#xD;
plant breeding and lab work to improve the micronutrient content of maize and wheat. At&#xD;
CIMMYT, this process is being used to boost pro-vitamin A and zinc levels in maize and iron and&#xD;
zinc concentrations in wheat.&#xD;
Boosting the micronutrient content of crops through biofortification can help tackle hidden&#xD;
hunger, simultaneously improving human health and economic growth leading to improved&#xD;
international development.&#xD;
In order to shed light on the important role maize and wheat play in global nutrition, CIMMYT&#xD;
celebrated the dietary value of these food staples throughout the month of June 2015. We asked&#xD;
you to send in your favorite maize and wheat-based recipes to be compiled into this cookbook.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-10-14T21:43:30Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2015-10-14T21:43:30Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2015</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/4485</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>4485</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_4485</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_4</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613913</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:42Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>