<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Breeding and disseminating quality protein maize (QPM) for Africa</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krivanek, A.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De Groote, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gunaratna, N.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diallo, A.O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friesen, D.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Quality protein maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>opaque-2</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>en-modifiers</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>aa-modifiers</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plant breeding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dissemination</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Impact assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Human nutrition</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Quality protein maize (QPM) describes a range of maize cultivars with twice the content of limiting amino acids lysine and tryptophan compared with conventional maize, and has been developed to help reduce human malnutrition in areas where protein deficiency is prevalent and where maize is the major protein source in the diet, as in various parts of Sub-Saharan Africa (SSA). The International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT), in collaboration with the International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA) and the National Agricultural Research Systems (NARS) in 17 countries of SSA, has developed a broad range of QPM cultivars responding to the needs of different countries and agroecological zones. Commercial QPM seed is currently available in all collaborating countries and, based on average 2003-2005 seed production, approximately 200,000 hectares of land are being planted to QPM cultivars.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-30T05:24:30Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-30T05:24:30Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2007</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3045</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.academicjournals.org/AJB/abstracts/abs2007/19Feb/Krivanek%20et%20al.htm</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Africa</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255146</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Africa</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255146</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3045</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3045</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:48Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>