<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Allelic variation at the TaZds-A1 locus on wheat chromosome 2A and development of a functional marker in common wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dong Chang-hai</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ma Zhi-ying</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xia Xian-Chun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang Li-Ping</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Triticum aestivum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Functional marker</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>QTL</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>æ-carotene desaturase</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>ZDS</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>zeta)-carotene desaturase (ZDS) is a key enzyme for carotenoid biosynthesis, demonstrating high association with the yellow pigment (YP) content in wheat grain. Cloning ZDS gene and developing functional markers are important for marker-assisted selection in wheat breeding. In the present study, the full-length DNA sequence of a ZDS gene on wheat chromosome 2A, designated TaZds-A1, was cloned, with 14 exons and 13 introns, and it has an open reading frame (ORF) of 1 707 bp, encoding 568 amino acid residues. A co-dominant functional marker, YP2A-1, was designed based on the polymorphisms of two alleles at the locus, TaZds-A1a and TaZds-A1b, yielding 183- and 179-bp fragments in TaZds-A1a and TaZds-A1b genotypes, respectively. A new QTL for YP content was detected on chromosome 2A, co-segregating with the functional marker YP2A-1 and TaZds-A1; it explained 11.3% of the phenotypic variance for YP content in a doubled haploid (DH) population from Zhongyou 9507/CA9632. Among 217 Chinese wheat cultivars and advanced lines, the average grain YP content of 126 cultivars with TaZds-A1b allele was 7.8% higher than that of 91 cultivars with TaZds-A1a allele.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:55Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:55Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2012</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>2095-3119</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1906</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2095311912600999</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1906</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1906</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:36Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>