<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bread wheat, durum wheat, and synthetic hexaploid wheat in saline and non-saline soils</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Acevedo, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Silva, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fraga, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pagas, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mujeeb-Kazi, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Triticum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Injurious factors</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plant breeding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soft wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil salinity</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Triticum aestivum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Saline soils</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Intraspecific hybridization</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research projects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genetic variation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hard wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Salt tolerance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Interspecific hybridization</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wheats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Triticum turgidum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Mexico</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Triticum durum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hexaploidy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Genetic improvement of crops for salt tolerance will become ever more important as it becomes necessary to cultivate marginal soils. The work reported here evaluated the intra- and interspecific variability in yield response to soil salinity of four Triticum groups: synthetic hexaploid wheats (T. turgidum x T. tauschii), bread wheats (T. aestivum L.), durum wheats (T. turgidum L.), and a reference group of salt tolerant bread wheats. The yield potential of these genotypes and their salt tolerance per se were also evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
The test genotypes were grown in five environments (two locations and three years) variably affected by soil salinity. The mean grain yield ranged from 1,805 to 5,788 kg/ha. The bread wheat, durum wheat, and salinity reference groups of genotypes had significantly higher yields than the synthetic hexaploids. The synthetic hexaploid group showed the characteristics of unimproved wheat: late flowering, tall plant height, low number of grains per ear, and a low harvest index, which resulted in high yield stability but low grain yield. The best adapted genetic materials belonged to the bread wheat and reference groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
The salinity reference group had the highest grain and biomass yields in the lowest yielding environment. The synthetic and bread wheat groups did not show variability for biomass yield, while variability for both biomass and grain yield was nil in the durum wheat group. Soil salinity tolerance was evaluated using a tolerance index. Improved bread wheats, including those in the reference group, showed higher yield potential and better salt tolerance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:17:38Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:17:38Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1999</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:isbn>970-648-028-5</dc:isbn>
  <dc:issn>0187-7787</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1238</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:relation>CIMMYT Wheat Special Report (WPSR)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Mexico</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3996063</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1238</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1238</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:10Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>