<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Specialty maize varieties in Mexico: a case study in market-driven agro-biodiversity conservation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Keleman, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hellin, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>There is growing interest in the extent to which market opportunities for local crops can bridge the gap between poverty alleviation and in situ conservation. We explore this issue through case studies of the blue and pozole maize specialty markets in the Mexican central highlands. Both markets utilize maize landraces that are cultivated predominantly by smallholder farmers. The pozole maize value chain relies on localized production and infrastructure investment that contributes to value-adding activities such as producing pre-cooked pozole. Blue maize, meanwhile, is more widely cultivated, and although there are fewer opportunities for farmers to add value, this grain feeds into small-scale, largely female-run businesses. Both markets have the potential to contribute to local livelihood improvements and in situ conservation, but careful policy design would be necessary to scale up these markets without diminishing their benefits.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2009</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2160</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2160</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2160</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:54Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>