<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Village surveys for technology uptake monitoring: Case of tillage dynamics in the trans-gangetic plains</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Erenstein, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>Agricultural research and development (R&amp;D) would benefit from reliable yet cheap technology uptake indicators to guide decision making. The paper explores the use of village surveys to monitor technology use and illustrates this through two empirical case studies into tillage dynamics in the Trans-Gangetic Plains in northwest India. The first case study is a revisit of 50 communities surveyed earlier in Haryana State. The second case study is a new and wider representative sample of 120 villages across Haryana and Punjab States. The case studies illustrate that after an initial rapid spread of tractor-drawn zero tillage drills for wheat seeding in these intensive systems, the zero + reduced tillage area seems to have stabilized there at between a fifth and a quarter of the wheat area. Conventional tillage for wheat continues to decline, with an increased use of rotavators making up the difference ? but its intensive shallow tillage goes against the conservation agriculture tenets. The paper illustrates the potential of village surveys to provide timely and cost-effective feedback to agricultural R&amp;D.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:43Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:43Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2010</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0014-4797</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2183</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://bit.ly/ZLlnZh</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2183</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2183</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:54Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>