<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Allelic variation at the Glu-D3 locus in Chinese bread wheat and effects on dough properties, pan bread and noodle qualities</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Liu, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ma, W.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, J.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xia, X.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peña-Bautista, R.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Triticum aestivum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Glu-D3</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Allelic variation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>bread-making quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Chinese noodle quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>SDS-PAGE</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Glutenin subunit alleles at the Glu-D3 locus and their effects on dough properties, pan bread, and dry white Chinese noodle (DWCN) qualities were investigated using 106 winter and facultative wheat cultivars and advanced lines. Allele Glu-D3c (42.5%) was the most frequent glutenin subunit, followed by Glu-D3b (25.5%) and Glu-D3a (23.6%). Glu-D3d and Glu-D3f occurred in only three and six cultivars, respectively. The effect of Glu-D3 was significant forDWCN quality, accounting for up to 16% of the variation, but there were no significant differences between individual Glu-D3 alleles on dough properties and qualities of DWCNand pan bread. Interaction effects Glu-A1 × Glu-D3 and Glu-B1 × Glu-D3 were significant for DWCN quality and loaf volume. More work is needed to understand the effects of Glu-D3 variation on the determination of dough properties and end-use quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:28Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:28Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2009</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2724</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2724</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2724</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:04Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>