<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Narrowing the wheat gap in Sub-Saharan Africa: A review of consumption and production issues</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Morris, M.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Byerlee, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Wheats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food production</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food consumption</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production factors</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Economic analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food policies</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Africa</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Many African countries stand at the crossroads with respect to wheat. They may choose to let recent trends continue in which case imported wheat will likely become a staple food for most urban consumers. Alternatively, if African countries want to avoid a high level of dependence on imported wheat, appropriate policy decisions must be taken now to manage wheat production and consumption. This paper reviews some of the options available to African policy makers for managing wheat consumption in the short to medium run and describes economic factors that influence the potential for increasing domestic wheat production over the longer run. Policy reforms implemented during the 1980s to curtail wheat consumption growth have apparently begun to take effect. However, efforts to build up domestic production capacity generally have been less successful. Recent studies are cited which demonstrate that wheat production in Africa can sometimes be efficient, but only under certain conditions that have not always been recognized by policy makers. Consideration needs to be taken into account of both sides of the wheat balance equation in order to design efficient and equitable policies and to determine appropriate levels of funding for future wheat research</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:22Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:22Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1993</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2023</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>Africa</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255146</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Africa</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255146</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2023</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2023</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:40Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>