<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>1995/96 World wheat facts and trends: Understanding global trends in the use of wheat diversity and international flows of wheat genetic resources</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>International trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Statistical analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plant breeding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Disease resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soft wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food consumption</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germplasm</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Trade policies</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research projects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genetic variation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wheats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Yields</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Innovation adoption</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genetic resources</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Economic analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food production</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This document describes wheat's origins and the flows of germplasm between various regions of the world. It summarizes some of the tools biological and social scientists use to measure genetic diversity. It examines patterns of bread wheat diversity in farmers' fields and evidence of genetic variation from breeding programs. Findings suggest that the often-invoked dichotomy between the gene-poor North and the gene-rich South has little validity for wheat. Findings also suggest that yield stability, resistance to rusts, pedigree complexity, and the number of modern cultivars in farmers' fields have all increased since the early years of the Green Revolution. Also included is a description of how economists approach the valuation of genetic diversity. Key policy issues for future research are identified. The report concludes with a brief overview of the world wheat situation in 1995/96, followed by selected statistics on production, consumption, and trade for all regions of the world.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:17:04Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:17:04Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1996</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0257-876X</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1215</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:relation>CIMMYT World Wheat Facts and Trends</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1215</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1215</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:56Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>