<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Collection and characterization of maize and upland rice populations cropped by poor farmers in the uplands of Panama's Azuero region</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Love, B. E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dreisigacker, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spaner, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Classification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genetic diversity</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Naming practices</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Phenotypes</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The conservation of crop genetic resources is an international priority and requires the continued collection and characterization of farmer varieties. We collected and characterized maize and upland rice populations cropped by farmers in Panama's Azuero region. The objective of our study was to evaluate the crop genetic diversity of farmer varieties of maize and upland rice grown by poor farmers in Panama. We found that: (1) farmers' naming practices only partially corresponded to genetic relationships and were the strongest for rice populations; (2) farmers' classification of populations as modern or "traditional" was reflected in phenotypic differences; (3) Panamanian maize populations were molecularly distinct from populations collected elsewhere in Latin America; and (4) heterogeneous rice populations were common and heterogeneity was often due to admixture of recognized farmer varieties. Our results indicate that poor farmers in Panama continue to farm "traditional" varieties that harbour genetic diversity of interest. There has, however, been substantial adoption of "modern" varieties.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:47Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:47Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2008</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1479-2621</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1850</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://bit.ly/XuQGnA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Panama</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3703430</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1850</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1850</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:45Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>