<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pathotype determination of the cereal cyst nematode, Heterodera avenae (Wollenweber, 1924) in the Eastern Mediterranean Region in Turkey</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Imren, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Toktay, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bozbuga, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dababat, A.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Elekcioglu, I.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>nematode</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>susceptible</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Virulence</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Karlik (Adana-Saricam), Imece (Hatay-Kirikhan) and Beþaslan (Hatay-Reyhanli) populations were used to determine the pathotype of the cereal cyst nematode, Heterodera avenae, in the Eastern Mediterranean Region of Turkey. Pathotype of H. avenae were investigated by using ?The International Test Assortment of Cereal Cultivars?. The test was conducted on twelve barley, six oat, six wheat and four control lines (milan, seri, silverstar and croc). Test materials were grouped by three nematode populations virulence on resistance (Rha?E?, Rha1, Rha2, Rha3, Cre1) and nonresistance genes variety and lines. According to results, Rha1 and Rha3 genes gave a resistance response but Rha2 and Cre1 did not. As a result, all populations demonstrated similar reactions and the three nematode populations were consistent with reactions for the Ha21 pathotype of the Ha1 group. This result is the first report on determining of the H. avenae pathotype in Turkey.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:58Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:58Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2012</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1010-6960</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2943</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>Turkey</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/298795</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2943</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2943</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:09Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>