<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Livelihoods and agro-ecological gradients: A meso-level analysis in the Indo-Gangetic Plains, India</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Erenstein, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorpe, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Livelihood analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Rice-wheat systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop-livestock systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>South Asia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Village survey</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Eco-regional research</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Rice-wheat systems in the Indo-Gangetic Plains (IGP) have long exemplified South Asia's agricultural transformation through the Green Revolution. The same systems now also typify the post-Green Revolution stagnation and equity challenges, despite receiving considerable attention from the research and development (R&amp;D) community. The apparent homogeneity of vast irrigated plains masks significant diversity in assets, livelihood strategies and livelihood outcomes. The paper analyzes the rural livelihoods and underlying agro-ecological gradients in the IGP drawing on village surveys and secondary data as characterization tools. The contribution of the paper is twofold: (i) new knowledge of the socio-economic circumstances in farming communities across the Indian IGP to enhance the effectiveness and efficiency of R&amp;D interventions and particularly poverty alleviation; and (ii) an illustration of a novel approach to operationalize livelihood analysis at the meso-level so as to address spatial scale issues and link microlevel contextual realities across a vast geographical area. The agricultural R&amp;D community needs to incorporate this socio-economic diversity more proactively into its R&amp;D agenda if it is to succeed in sustaining productivity gains, improving rural livelihoods equitably, and securing environmental sustainability in this important eco-region.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:44Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:44Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2011</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0308-521X</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2193</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>India</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1269750</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2193</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2193</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:55Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>