<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The farming systems of the Texizapan watershed, Sierra de Santa Marta, Veracruz, Mexico</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rice, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Erenstein, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Godinez, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Wet season</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Human feeding</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kidney beans</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Veracruz</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zea mays</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production factors</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutritional status</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cropping systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Agricultural development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plant production</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Yields</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sustainability</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Storage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Seed storage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Phaseolus vulgaris</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dry season</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Intercropping</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The main farming systems of the Texizapan watershed in southern Veracruz, Mexico (200-1,640 meters above sea level) were characterized through a formal survey in 1995. Farm-level data included an inventory of resources (human, land, and capital), their use, and resource flows (both intra- and inter-household). Field-level data, particularly on input use and production, were gathered for the major crops, maize and coffee. Maize was the main food crop, grown by all households. Coffee was the main cash crop, but production was limited to higher elevations. The maize cropping system was relatively land extensive and labor intensive; all practice were entirely manual. External input use was relatively limited, emphasizing herbicides. Half the farmers reported using fertilizers, but levels were generally low and use of improved maize varieties rare. All farmers used burning as a land preparation practice prior to maize planting. Maize yields in the main season averaged less than a 1 t/ha. Maize was generally intercropped with beans and other crops, although intercrop yields also appeared low. Maize producttion in the minor season was more widespread than previously thought, although yields were extremely low. Given the low yields, high labor input, and limited external input use, returns to maize cultivation were low. Even so, maize cultivation was expected to continue in the study area, in view of the households' consumption needs and limited alternative income opportunities. Half the sample reported being net consumers of maize, and the need to purchase beans - the major protein source - was even more widespread. In view of the limited number of other food sources available locally and constraints on disposable income, the nutritional status of the households warrants closer attention. The major challenge facing producers was that of sustainably raising productivity to provide for consumption and other needs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:08:32Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:08:32Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1998</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:isbn>970-648-010-2</dc:isbn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/959</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:relation>CIMMYT NRG Copublication</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT *PSSM</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Mexico</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3996063</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Mexico</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3996063</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>959</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_959</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:52Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>