<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Implicit prices of indigenous bull traits in crop-livestock mixed production systems of Ethiopia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kassie, G.T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Abdulai, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wollny, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>This study examines the bull trait preferences of cattle buyers and estimates the relative willingness to pay for the preferred attributes. Data were generated using choice experiment method in five markets in central Ethiopia. Standard and Heterogeneity in Mean (H-M) Random Parameters Logit (RPL) models were used to analyze buyers? preferences for traits, while kernel density estimators were employed to examine the distribution of the willingness to pay for the individual traits. The results show that cattle buyers of central Ethiopia assign high values for good traction potential, big body size, disease resistance, calf vigor, and for places of origin when choosing bulls in the market. The preferences cattle buyers have for these attributes do vary essentially due to differences in occupation, education and age. The main implication of the findings is the necessity of identification and reckoning of trait preferences while designing crossbreeding efforts meant to sustain development of cattle production. Comprehensive and informed approach in this regard will also contribute in reducing the erosion of the genetic diversity of the indigenous animal genetic resources.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:53Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:53Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2012</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1017-6772</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2255</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1467-8268.2010.00244.x/abstract</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Ethiopia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/337996</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Ethiopia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/337996</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2255</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2255</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:55Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>