<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparative analyses of LMW glutenin alleles in bread wheat using allele-specific PCR and SDS-PAGE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ram, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sharmaa, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Verma, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tyagi, B.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peña-Bautista, R.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Glutenins</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>PCR</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>SDS-PAGE</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>One hundred and eighty-two bread wheat cultivars developed in India were characterized for low molecular weight (LMW) glutenins using SDS-PAGE and allele-specific polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to assess allelic diversity encoded by Glu-3 loci, as well as their utility for correctly identifying different alleles. SDS-PAGE indicated Glu-A3c is present in 64.6% of the cultivars, Glu-A3b in 13.8%, Glu-A3d in 12.7% and Glu-A3e/f in 8.8%. Seven types of alleles were present at the Glu-B3 locus: Glu-B3b (29.3%), Glu-B3g (27.0%), Glu-B3h (13.8%), Glu-B3i (16.1%), Glu-B3j (12.1%), Glu-B3c (0.6%) and Glu-B3d (1.1%). SDS-PAGE found three types of Glu-D3 alleles: Glu-D3a (30.2%), Glu-D3b (67.1%) and Glu-D3c (2.7%). However, PCR found two different alleles in cultivars classified as carrying Glu-D3a and three alleles in those identified as carrying Glu-D3b cultivars, indicating a more complex nature of the Glu-D3 locus. In conclusion, the data found greater consistency between the SDS-PAGE and PCR amplification patterns of alleles such as Glu-A3c, Glu-A3d, Glu-B3g, Glu-B3h and Glu-B3i, and less consistency between those same patterns in the Glu-A3b, Glu-A3e/f and Glu-B3b alleles. More studies are needed in order to achieve unambiguous identification of the Glu-3 alleles and thereby allow their greater utility in germplasm evaluation and breeding.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:44Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:44Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2011</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0733-5210</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2852</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>India</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1269750</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2852</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2852</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:07Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>