<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impact of zero tillage adoption on household welfare in Pakistan</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ali, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Erenstein, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Adoption</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Impact Evaluation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zero tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Propensity Score Matching</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Punjab</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pakistan</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The current study was carried out to estimate the impact of zero tillage technology adoption on household welfare in Pakistan. For the study cross sectional data set was collected from 234 households in the rice-wheat area of Pakistani Punjab. The data was collected through stratified random sampling technique from 3 main districts of rice-wheat area namely Gujranwala, Sheikhupura and Hafizabad. The empirical analysis was carried out by employing the propensity score matching approach to correct for potential sample selection biased ness that may arise due to systematic differences between adopters and non adopters. The empirical result indicates that adoption of zero tillage technology has positive and significant impact on wheat yield and household income while non significant impact on rice yield. Most importantly the adoption of zero tillage technology can help to reduce poverty among rural households in the range of 8-10 percent.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T18:01:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2014-03-05T18:01:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2013</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1686-9141</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3460</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:pdf>http://www.ijat-aatsea.com/pdf/v9_n7_13_December/5_IJAT_2013_9(7)_Akhter%20Ali_Agronomy.pdf</dc:pdf>
  <dc:geotag>Pakistan</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1168579</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Pakistan</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1168579</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3460</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3460</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:45Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>