<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genetic yield gains and changes in associated traits of CIMMYT spring bread wheat in a 'Historic' set representing 30 years of breeding</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lopes, M.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reynolds, M.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Manes, Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, R.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crossa, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Braun, H.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>The genetic yield progress of 26 spring wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) advanced lines released by the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Centre (CIMMYT) in the period from 1977 to 2008 was evaluated in the selection environment in Mexico as well as at a set of target environments in Asia and Africa. In Mexico, grain yield progress was signifi cantly linear and about 0.7% yr&amp;#8722;1 and yield was associated with fewer days to heading, cooler canopy temperature at grain fi lling, and increased stay-green and thousand kernel weight. These results suggested that changes in the former traits at least partially explain the yield progress. When genetic yield progress was measured in subsets of sites in Asia and Africa grouped into high, intermediate, and low yielding, the genetic yield progress was 0.9, 0.7, and 0.5% yr-1, respectively. We conclude that there is no evidence that genetic gains to increase yield have slowed down in wheat lines released by CIMMYT.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:52Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:52Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2012</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0011-183X</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2904</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>Mexico</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3996063</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Mexico</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3996063</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Africa</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255146</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2904</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2904</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:07Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>