<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genetic diversity in conventional and synthetic wheats with drought and salinity tolerance based on AFLP</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Das, M.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bai, G.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mujeeb-Kazi, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>AFLP</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dna fingerprinting</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genetic diversity</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Synthetic wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Genetic diversity, among fourteen drought and twenty-seven salinity tolerant conventional and synthetic wheat (Triticum sp.) accessions containing different sources of the D genome, was assessed using amplified fragment length polymorphism (AFLP). The wheat accessions were analyzed with 20 EcoRI/MseI primer combinations. Among 918 fragments scored, 368 were polymorphic across all 41 wheat accessions, 348 were polymorphic among the accessions with drought tolerance and 310 were polymorphic among the accessions with salinity tolerance. Similarity coefficients among all accessions based on Jaccard¿s coefficient ranged from 0.18 to 0.92 with an average of 0.53 ± 0.01; among drought tolerant accessions, from 0.16 to 0.79 with an average of 0.43 ± 0.02; and among salinity tolerant accessions, from 0.16 to 0.92 with an average of 0.57 ± 0.01. Polymorphic information content (PIC) among all accessions ranged from 0.05 to 0.50 with an average PIC of 0.30 ± 0.01; among drought tolerant accessions, from 0.13 to 0.50 with an average PIC of 0.37 ± 0.01; and among salinity tolerant accessions, from 0.07 to 0.50 with an average PIC of 0.29 ± 0.01. Cluster and principal component analysis showed distinct groups of accessions both within drought and salinity tolerant entries. These accessions possess a substantial amount of genetic diversity and would be very valuable materials for breeding wheat with drought and salinity tolerance</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:32Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:32Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2007</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1730</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://pubs.aic.ca/doi/abs/10.4141/P06-013</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1730</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1730</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:36Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>