<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Review on low-molecular-weight glutenin subunits and their coding genes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zhao Xian-lin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xia Xian-chun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu Li</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sun Qi-xin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Bread wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>LMW-GS</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>gene</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Allelic variation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The low-molecular-weight glutenin subunit (LMW-GS) of wheat is about 1/3 of the amount in seed storage proteins and has great effects on dough extensibility and food processing quality. It has thus became one of the main factors for wheat quality improvement. However, resolution of the LMW-GS and the scoring of their alleles by direct analysis of proteins are challenging to work with due to the larger number of expressed subunits and their overlapping mobility with the abundant gliadin proteins. In this paper, scientists reviewed the nomenclature and structure features of LMW-GS, their coding gene loci on chromosomes and allelic variation, the registered genes in Genbank and classification, and their relations with. We also discussed the identification of LMW-GS genes and their development of molecular markers based on the author&amp;rsquo;s own research results, in order to provide a theoretical basis for using LMW-GS in breeding quality wheat cultivar.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:00Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:00Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2007</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2556</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>zho</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://211.155.251.135:81/Jwk_zgnykx/EN/abstract/abstract13524.shtml</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2556</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2556</dc:apiid>
  <dc:lexvo>http://lexvo.org/id/iso639-3/zho</dc:lexvo>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:11Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>