<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Karnal Bunt (Neovossia indica) Disease of Wheat Conference; Ciudad Obregon, Sonora, Mexico; 16-18 Apr 1984. Proceedings</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Wheats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tilletia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Mexico</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Disease resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sonora</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Smuts</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Chemical control</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fungicides</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The conference provided an informal forum for the presentation and discussion of current research efforts related to Karnal bunt and an opportunity for Mexican, Canadian and American scientist/administrators to personally examine and appraise the Karnal bunt disease situation in Northwest Mexico. Highlights of the presentations made at the conference are summarized and include: Overview of CIMMYT's Karnal bunt program; laboratory evaluation of chemical seed treatments to control teliospore germination; field evaluation of systematic fungicides as seed treatments; laboratory evaluation off fungicides to control germination of secondary</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-13T01:09:54Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2014-03-13T01:09:54Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1984</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Grey literature</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3986</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Mexico</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3996063</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3986</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3986</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2015-05-28T17:12:11Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>