<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>CIMMYT 2000-2001 world wheat overview and outlook: Developing no-till packages for small-scale farmers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ekboir, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Economic development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Statistical analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental factors</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research institutions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production factors</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research projects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Small farms</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Developing Countries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food production</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Part 1 of this report (which is a continuation of CIMMYT's World Wheat Facts and Trends series under a new name) explores issues related to the development and adoption of no-till technology, especially in small-scale agriculture. It describes no-till's special features, the innovation systems through which the technology evolves, a new framework for the socioeconomic study of the development and adoption of no-till, and the methodological difficulties involved in measuring no-till's benefits and adoption. This information provides the context for a series of six case studies of no-till experiences among small-scale farmers in Latin America, Africa, and Asia (and largely in wheat cropping systems). Part 1 concludes by discussing key factors conditioning the effectiveness of no-til1 programs for small-scale farmers, including the implications for national and international agricultural research. Part 2 documents that wheat yield potential has grown more rapidly in marginal compared to favorable environments in recent years, explores the reasons for this growth, and discusses the implications for future wheat breeding research for marginal areas. Part 3 tracks current and future trends in the global wheat market, with special attention to policy in the United States, European Union, and China. Part 4 provides statistics on wheat production, consumption, yields, and other variables.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:18:12Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:18:12Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2002</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1665-1871</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1253</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:relation>CIMMYT World Wheat Overview and Outlook</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Africa</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255146</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1253</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1253</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:10Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>