<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Distribution of genes associated with noodle qualities in Sichuan wheat cultivars</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chen Jing</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang Xiao-ke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sun Wen-yu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wu Ling</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li Li-rong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yu Mao-qun</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Triticum aestivum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>noodle quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>waxy protein</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Polyphenol oxidase (PPO)</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Selection of waxy protein W x2B 1 null type and decreasing polyp henol oxidase activity can greatly cont ribute to the genetic improvement of noodle quality. In t he current paper , 104 wheat culti2 vars and advanced lines f rom Sichuan province were used to identify t he allelic variation at t hree loci , W x2B 1 , P PO22A and P PO22D , meanwhile t he starch pasting properties of 59 wheat lines f rom t he 104 genotypes were determined. The result s showed t hat cultivar s f rom Sichuan displayed desired starch character s. The f requency of P PO22A b and P PO22Da cont rolling low PPO activity were 42. 3 % and 83. 6 % , respectively. The f requency of W x2B 1b was 26. 9 %. Significant difference in four starch viscosity parameter s , including peak viscosity , breakdown , final viscosity and set back , were ob2 served between the Wx2B1 null type wheat and t he normal type. Mianyang 26 , Chuanmai 107 and Chuanmai 43 are important parent s for noodle wheat breeding. As an accurate and efficient technolo2 gy , multiplex PCR can be very usef ul in marker assisted selection targeting for complex t raits like Noodle quality</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:12Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:12Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2007</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2616</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>zho</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2616</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2616</dc:apiid>
  <dc:lexvo>http://lexvo.org/id/iso639-3/zho</dc:lexvo>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:11Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>