<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Identification of 1BL/1RS translocation based on mixograph parameters in common wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Liu Jian-Jun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiao Yong-Gui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cheng Dun-Gong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Li Hao-Sheng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu Li</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Song Jian-Min</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu Ai-Feng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhao Zheng-Dong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>lBL/1RS translocation has been widely used for improving agronomic performance and disease resistance in wheat (Triticum aestivum L.), however, it has strong negative effect on processing quality.  To develop a method for 1BL/1RS translocation identification with mixograph parameters, 404 advanced lines from 146 crosses in 2005-2006 (experiment I) and 175 advanced lines and main cultivars of Shandong province (experiment II) in 2005-2006 and 2006-2007 cropping seasons were used in this study. All materials were sown under irrigation condition in a randomized complete design with 1 replication in Jinan. The genetic effect of lBL/lRS translocation on mixograph parameters was investigated. The variations of mixograph parameters under different combinations of the high molecular weight glutenin subunits (HMW-GS) and low molecular weight glutenin subunits (HMW-GS) were also analyzed.  1BL/1RS translocation lines showed significantly shorter mixing time, less bandwidth of peak and bandwidth after 1 min peak, and higher angle of descent and the bandwidth ratio (the ratio of bandwidth of peak/bandwidth after l min peak) in comparison with non-1BL/1RS translocation lines.  It indicated that the lBL/lRS translocation has deleterious effects on mixograph parameters.  Mixograph of the lBL/J RS translocation was characterized with the bandwidth sharply declining and narrowing after l min peak, and increasing the bandwidth ratio, whereas the bandwidth of non-lBL/lRS translocations declined gently after l min peak or had a longer mixing tolerance, and had a little variation about the bandwidth ratio.  Furthermore, 85.2% (experiment I) and 96.8% (experiment II) accuracies were achieved in grouping the Lbl/lRS translocation and non-1BL/1RS translocation on the basis of the band width ratio, i.e., 1BL/1RS translocation line had a value smaller than 1.6.  Although the Glu-B3 alleles showed better quality parameters when HMW-GS 5+10 was presented, it was still the most unfavorable allele on mixograph parameters among all Glu-B3 alleles.  Therefore, mixograph parameters could be used to determine the rheological properties and the presence of 1BL/1RS translocation</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:29Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:29Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2009</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2732</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>zho</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2732</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2732</dc:apiid>
  <dc:lexvo>http://lexvo.org/id/iso639-3/zho</dc:lexvo>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:06Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>