<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>In situ conservation of crops and their relatives: A review of current status and prospects for wheat and maize</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dempsey, G.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Triticum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wheats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Innovation adoption</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Genetic resources</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Zea mays</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>High yielding varieties</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germplasm conservation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research projects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper reviews the current status and prospects for in situ conservation of maize and wheat and their relatives. The caricature of in situ conservation-that it imposes cultural stasis and isolation on marginal communities-is avoided as simplistic. The prospect of combining crop improvement with the retention of useful diversity is examined. Such initiatives are seen as benefiting from both farmer and breeder expertise. Local varieties and production systems are not necessarily seen as incompatible with introduced germplasm. The need for protecting wild relatives of wheat and maize from human-induced pressures is discussed, as is the idea of supporting diversity-rich farm systems (with minimal individual subsidy and institution building) that are compatible with introduced varieties and improved yields. Maintaining useful diversity is seen as involving both conservation efforts and appropriate breeding interventions. Questions about the wisdom of relying on stored genetic resources while evolution and social change continue in and around the field are examined.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T04:22:59Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T04:22:59Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1996</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1405-2830</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/575</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:relation>CIMMYT NRG Paper</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>575</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_575</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:41Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>