<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Concerted changes in N and C primary metabolism in alfalfa (Medicago sativa) under water restriction</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aranjuelo, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tcherkez, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Molero, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gilard, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Avice, J-C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nogues, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Alfalfa</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>C/N</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Drought</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>metabolomic</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>nodule</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>proteomic</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Although the mechanisms of nodule N2 fixation in legumes are now well documented, some uncertainty remains on the metabolic consequences of water deficit. In most cases, little consideration is given to other organs and, therefore, the coordinated changes in metabolism in leaves, roots, and nodules are not well known. Here, the effect of water restriction on exclusively N2-fixing alfalfa (Medicago sativa L.) plants was investigated, and proteomic, metabolomic, and physiological analyses were carried out. It is shown that the inhibition of nitrogenase activity caused by water restriction was accompanied by concerted alterations in metabolic pathways in nodules, leaves, and roots. The data suggest that nodule metabolism and metabolic exchange between plant organs nearly reached homeostasis in asparagine synthesis and partitioning, as well as the N demand from leaves. Typically, there was (i) a stimulation of the anaplerotic pathway to sustain the provision of C skeletons for amino acid (e.g. glutamate and proline) synthesis; (ii) re-allocation of glycolytic products to alanine and serine/glycine; and (iii) subtle changes in redox metabolites suggesting the implication of a slight oxidative stress. Furthermore, water restriction caused little change in both photosynthetic efficiency and respiratory cost of N2 fixation by nodules. In other words, the results suggest that under water stress, nodule metabolism follows a compromise between physiological imperatives (N demand, oxidative stress) and the lower input to sustain catabolism.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-12-09T20:48:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-12-09T20:48:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2013</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0022-0957</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3371</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>http://jxb.oxfordjournals.org/content/64/4/1.1.abstract</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>3371</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_3371</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:10Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>