<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impact of CGIAR training in the developing world: Bangladesh, a case study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Meisner, C.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Diffusion of information</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Training programmes</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>CGIAR</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Innovation adoption</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Training courses</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Diffusion of research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Developing Countries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two centers belonging to the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR) - CIMMYT and the International Rice Research Institute (IRRI) - have assisted research efforts at the Banglasdesh Agriculture Research Institute and the Bangladesh Rice Research Institute for more than 25 years. Some of this assistance has involved sending Bangladeshi scientists abroad for training at either CIMMYT in Mexico or IRRI in the Philippines. After so many years and so many scientists' attendance at these courses, questions naturally arise as to how useful and relevant the training is and how much it has impacted the participants' professional development, the research capabilities of their perspective research institutions,and national cereal production. In an attempt to provide an answer to these questions, in 1995 survey was conducted among Bangladeshi scientists who attended courses at CIMMYT and IRRI between 1968 and 1994. A questionnaire focusing on aspects such as the relevance and applicability of the course content was sent to more than 100 former trainees. A majority of them filled out and returned the questionnaire. This paper attempts to interpret the respondents' perceptions of the training they received and the effect it has had on them and their institutions over the years. Their responses suggest that CGIAR training has had significant positive impacts on Bangladeshi research institutions and, through them, on national cereal producion.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:17:11Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:17:11Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1997</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:isbn>968-6923-97-7</dc:isbn>
  <dc:issn>0187-7787</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1220</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:relation>CIMMYT Wheat Special Report (WPSR)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Bangladesh</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1210997</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Bangladesh</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1210997</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Mexico</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/3996063</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1220</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1220</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:56Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>