<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Characterisation of high- and low-molecular-weight glutenin subunit genes in Chinese winter wheat cultivars and advanced lines using allele-specific markers and SDS-PAGE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yang, F.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, L.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, J.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xinyao He</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, X.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shang, X.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yang, W.X.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xia, X.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Triticum aestivum L.</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>HMW-GS</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>LMW-GS</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>SDS-PAGE</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Wheat end-use product quality is highly influenced by the composition and quantity of high- and low-molecular-weight glutenin subunits (HMW-GS and LMW-GS). In the present study, 224 Chinese wheat cultivars and advanced lines were characterised for the HMW-GS and LMW-GS with allele-specific PCR markers and sodium-dodecyl-sulfate polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis (SDS-PAGE). The results showed that 56 cultivars (25.0%) carried the allele Glu-D1-1d (Dx5), while 80 cultivars (35.7%) with the allele Glu-B1-2a (By8) produced a 527-bp specific band. Fourteen genotypes (6.3%) with the allele Glu-B1e (Bx20) yielded a 701-bp amplicon with the marker Mar and a 753-bp specific PCR fragment with the marker ZSBy9aF1/R3. Glu-B1h (Bx14+By15) was present in only 1 genotype, and 2 cultivars contained the allele Glu-B1f (Bx13+By16) identified with the marker ZSBy9F2/R2. Four genotypes (1.8%) with the allele Glu-B1-1d (Bx6) gave 695-bp and 830-bp bands, and 5 genotypes (2.2%) with the allele Glu-B1i (Bx17+By18) amplified a 659-bp fragment using the marker Bx. One hundred and six cultivars (47.3%) had the allele Glu-B1-2b (By9), amplifying a 663-bp fragment with the marker ZSBy9aF1/R3; 34 genotypes (15.8%) contained the allele Glu-B3d, generating a 662-bp PCR fragment with the marker gluB3d. Fifteen cultivars (7.0%) with the allele Glu-B3b yielded 1570-bp and 750-bp PCR amplicons with the markers gluB3b and gluB3bef, respectively. The allele Glu-B3h was found in 7 cultivars, generating a 1022-bp PCR fragment with the marker gluB3h. The genotypes detected by SDS-PAGE were mostly consistent with those identified by molecular markers, confirming the utility of the molecular markers. The information for the HMW-GS and LMW-GS in Chinese wheat cultivars will be useful in wheat breeding programs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:38Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:38Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2010</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1836-0947</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2798</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2798</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2798</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:06Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>