<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genetic analysis of heat tolerance at anthesis in rice</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jagadish S.V.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cairns J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lafitte R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wheeler T.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Price A.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Craufurd P.Q.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>Genetic analysis of heat tolerance will help breeders produce rice (Oryza sativa L.) varieties adapted to future climates. An F6 population of 181 recombinant inbred lines of Bala (tolerant) x Azucena (susceptible) was screened for heat tolerance at anthesis by measuring spikelet fertility at 30°C (control) and 38°C (high temperature) in experiments conducted in the Philippines and the United Kingdom. The parents varied significantly for absolute spikelet fertility under control (79-87%) and at high temperature (2.9-47.1%), and for relative spikelet fertility (high temperature/control) at high temperature (3.7-54.9%). There was no correlation between spikelet fertility in control and high-temperature conditions and no common quantitative trait loci (QTLs) were identified. Two QTLs for spikelet fertility under control conditions were identified on chromosomes 2 and 4. Eight QTLs for spikelet fertility under high-temperature conditions were identified on chromosomes 1, 2, 3, 8, 10, and 11. The most significant heat-responsive QTL, contributed by Bala and explaining up to 18% of the phenotypic variation, was identified on chromosome 1 (38.35 mega base pairs on the rice physical genome map). This QTL was also found to influence plant height, explaining 36.6% of the phenotypic variation. A comparison with other studies of abiotic (drought, cold, salinity) stresses showed QTLs at similar positions on chromosomes 1, 3, 8, and 10, suggesting common underlying stress-responsive regions of the genome.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:46Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:46Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2010</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0011-183X</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1841</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:publisher>https://www.crops.org/publications/cs/abstracts/50/5/1633</dc:publisher>
  <dc:geotag>Philippines</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1694008</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1841</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1841</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:46Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>