<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sample size for detecting and estimating the proportion of transgenic plants with narrow confidence intervals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Montesinos Lopez, O.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Montesinos-Lopez, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crossa, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eskridge, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hernandez Suarez, C.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>adventitious presence of transgenic plants</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>confidence interval</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>confidence interval width</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>pool sampling</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Detecting the presence of genetically modified plants (adventitious presence of unwanted transgenic plants, AP) from outcrossing species such as maize requires a method that lowers laboratory costs without losing precision. Group testing is a procedure in which groups that contain several units (plants) are analysed without having to inspect individual plants, with the purpose of estimating the prevalence of AP in a population at a low cost without losing precision. When pool (group) testing is used to estimate the prevalence of AP (p), there are sampling procedures for calculating a confidence interval (CI); however, they usually do not ensure precision in the estimation of pags This research proposes a method to determine the number of pools (g), given a pool size (k), that ensures precision in the estimated proportion of AP (that is, it ensures a narrow CI). In addition, the study computes the maximum likelihood estimator of p under pool testing and its exact CI, considering the detection limit of  the laboratory, d, and the concentration of AP per unit (c). The proposed sample procedure involves two steps: (1) obtain a sample size that guarantees that the mean width of the CI (w) is narrower than the desired width (v); and (2) iteratively increase the sample size until w is smaller than the desired width (v) with a specified degree of certainty (g). Simulated data were created and tables are presented showing the different possible scenarios that a researcher may encounter. An R program is given and explained that will reproduce the results and make it easy for the researcher to create other scenarios.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:42Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:42Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2010</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0960-2585</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1814</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:publisher>http://bit.ly/10X6crx</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1814</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1814</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:46Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>