<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Milling and Chinese raw white noodle qualities of common wheat near-isogenic lines differing in puroindoline b alleles</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ma, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xia, X.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morris, C.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He Zhonghu</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>common wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Puroindoline alleles</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Near-isogenic lines</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Chinese raw white noodles</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Understanding the effects of different alleles at the puroindoline b (Pinb) locus on processing quality will provide crucial information for quality improvement. Seven near-isogenic lines (NILs) planted at two locations in the 2008 cropping season were used to determine the effect of puroindoline b alleles on milling performance and Chinese raw white noodle (CRWN) quality. The Pina-D1b/Pinb-D1a genotype possessed significantly higher values in grain hardness, protein content and starch damage than other genotypes, whereas the Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1d genotype had the lowest grain hardness and starch damage, with higher break flour yield, and less reduction flour yield, higher flour colour L*, and lower flour colour b*, than other genotypes. Farinograph parameters, except for water absorption, were not significantly affected by variation of puroindoline b alleles. Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1e had the highest peak viscosity, whereas the lowest value was observed in a Pina-D1b/Pinb-D1a genotype. For CRWN quality, higher noodle viscoelasticity was obtained in the genotype Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1e and Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1g, whereas Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1d had a lower smoothness score. Genotypes with Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1e and Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1g produced the best total noodle score. It was concluded that genotype Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1d had better milling qualities, whereas Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1e and Pina-D1a/Pinb-D1g had slightly superior CRWN qualities in comparison with other genotypes</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:27Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:27Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2009</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2720</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2720</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2720</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:04Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>