<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genetics and mapping of resistance to spore inoculum and culture filtrate of Phaeosphaeria nodorum in spring wheat line ND 735</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Singh, P.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mergoum, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Adhikari, T.B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ghavami, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kianian, S.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Stagonospora nodorum blotch</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Host-pathogen interaction</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Diversity arrays technology (DArT)</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Simple sequence repeat (SSR) markers</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Stagonospora nodorum blotch (SNB), caused by Phaeosphaeria nodorum, is one of the most devastating foliar diseases on wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) in the northern Great Plains of North America. This study was conducted, under controlled environmental conditions, to elucidate the genetics and map the resistance to SNB caused by spore inoculum and culture filtrate of P. nodorum isolate Sn2000. A hard red spring wheat population was developed from a cross between the susceptible cultivar Steele-ND and the resistant line ND 735 for this study. Two-leaf seedlings of the parents, F1 and F2 generations, and F2:6 recombinant-inbred lines (RILs) were inoculated with spore suspensions while independent two week old seedlings of segregating generations were infiltrated with culture filtrate. Disease reaction was assessed 8 days after inoculation based on a lesion-type scale while plants were evaluated for culture filtrate response four days after infiltration for the presence or absence of necrosis. Genetic analysis revealed that a single recessive gene, Tsn1, in ND 735 confers resistance to both spore suspension and culture filtrate of P. nodorum isolate Sn2000. Mapping analysis using Diversity Arrays Technology (DArT) and simple sequence repeat (SSR) markers indicates the gene, Tsn1, is located on the long arm of chromosome 5B and is flanked by the DArt markers wPt-8285 and wPt-3049 at a distance of 7.0 cM and 2.9 cM, respectively. This gene also controls resistance to tan spot caused by Pyrenophora tritici-repentis race 2. Results of this study reveal that wheat-P. nodorum interaction follows the toxin model of gene-for-gene hypothesis. Additionally, the finding of single gene control in the line ND 735 for both tan spot and SNB enhances the utility of the line ND 735 in wheat breeding program as a source of multiple disease resistance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:41Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2011</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>0261-2194</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2821</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2821</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2821</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:06Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>