<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Can everybody be well fed by 2020 without damaging natural resources?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pinstrup-Andersen, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pandya-Lorch, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food supply</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Resource conservation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental control</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Malnutrition</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Natural resources</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Human nutrition</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food production</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Failure to assure sustainable food security will foster the very conditions that will further destabilize and polarize the world in the years to come, with tremendous consequences for all people. This lecture discusses six kinds of action required for global food needs to be met without damage to the environment: selective strengthening of the capacity of developing-country governments; investing more in poor people; accelerating agricultural productivity; assuring sound management of natural resources; developing competitive markets; and expanding and realigning international development assistance. Projections of the incidence of malnutrition population growth, cereal supply and demand, cereal prices, and advances in food production underscore the seriousness of potential threats to food security and the environment. To illustrate the opportunities associated with alternative actions to mitigate threats to sustainable food security, the authors demonstrate how numbers of malnourished children would be affected under two scenarios, a pessimistic scenario (slow income growth and low investment in national and international agricultural research) and an optimistic scenario (rapid income growth and higher investment in national and international agricultural research, as well as investment in public goods such as health and education).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:08:06Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2012-01-06T05:08:06Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1997</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Books and monographs</dc:type>
  <dc:issn>1405-5112</dc:issn>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/939</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:relation>CIMMYT Distinguished Economist Lecture</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:publisher>CIMMYT</dc:publisher>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>939</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_939</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:52Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>