<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Linkage analysis and map construction in genetic populations of clonal F1 and double cross</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Clonal F1</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Double cross</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Linkage analysis</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study, we considered four categories of molecular markers based on the number of
distinguishable alleles at the marker locus and the number of distinguishable genotypes in clonal F1
progenies. For two marker loci, there are nine scenarios that allow the estimation of female, male, and/
or combined recombination frequencies. In a double cross population derived from four inbred lines, five
categories of markers are classified and another five scenarios are present for recombination frequency
estimation. Theoretical frequencies of identifiable genotypes were given for each scenario, from which the
maximum likelihood estimates of one or more of the three recombination frequencies could be estimated. If
there was no analytic solution, then Newton-Raphson method was used to acquire a numerical solution. We
then proposed to use an algorithm in Traveling Salesman Problem to determine the marker order. Finally,
we proposed a procedure to build the two haploids of the female parent and the two haploids of the male
parent in clonal F1. Once the four haploids were built, clonal F1 hybrids could be exactly regarded as
a double cross population. Efficiency of the proposed methods was demonstrated in simulated clonal F1
populations and one actual maize double cross. Extensive comparisons with software JoinMap4.1, OneMap,
and R/qtl show that the methodology proposed in this article can build more accurate linkage maps in
less time.</dc:description>
  <dc:pubDate>2015</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>JA</dc:type>
  <dc:pdf>http://www.g3journal.org/content/5/3/427.full.pdf+html?sid=d07d62ee-3d96-49e1-905d-0ba8763a6f3f</dc:pdf>
  <dc:publisher>Genetics Society of America,</dc:publisher>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_3</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613912</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:apiid>351598648</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cdocid>351598648</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:updated_date>2015-05-28T16:33:34Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>