<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fine scale genetic and physical mapping using interstitial deletion mutants of Lr34 /Yr18: a disease resistance locus effective against multiple pathogens in wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Spielmeyer, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, R.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McFadden, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wellings, C.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huerta-Espino, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kong, X.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Appels, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lagudah, E.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>The Lr34/Yr18 locus has contributed to durable, non-race specific resistance against leaf rust (Puccinia triticina) and stripe rust (P. striiformis f. sp. tritici) in wheat (Triticum aestivum). Lr34/Yr18 also cosegregates with resistance to powdery mildew (Pm38) and a leaf tip necrosis phenotype (Ltn1). Using a high resolution mapping family from a cross between near-isogenic lines in the &amp;ldquo;Thatcher&amp;rdquo; background we demonstrated that Lr34/Yr18 also cosegregated with stem rust resistance in the field. Lr34/Yr18 probably interacts with unlinked genes to provide enhanced stem rust resistance in &amp;ldquo;Thatcher&amp;rdquo;. In view of the relatively low levels of DNA polymorphism reported in the Lr34/Yr18 region, gamma irradiation of the single chromosome substitution line, Lalbahadur(Parula7D) that carries Lr34/Yr18 was used to generate several mutant lines. Characterisation of the mutants revealed a range of highly informative genotypes, which included variable size deletions and an overlapping set of interstitial deletions. The mutants enabled a large number of wheat EST derived markers to be mapped and define a relatively small physical region on chromosome 7DS that carried Lr34/Yr18. Fine scale genetic mapping confirmed the physical mapping and identified a genetic interval of less than 0.5 cM, which contained Lr34/Yr18. Both rice and Brachypodium genome sequences provided useful information for fine mapping of ESTs in wheat. Gene order was more conserved between wheat and Brachypodium than with rice but these smaller grass genomes did not reveal sequence information that could be used to identify a candidate gene for rust resistance in wheat. We predict that Lr34/Yr18 is located within a large insertion in wheat not found at syntenic positions in Brachypodium and rice.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:13Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:13Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2008</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2628</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2628</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2628</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:04Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>