<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Combining superior agronomic performance and terminal heat tolerance with resistance to spot blotch (Bipolaris sorokiniana) of wheat in the warm humid Gangetic Plains of South Asia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Joshi, A.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ortiz-Ferrara, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crossa, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singh, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sharma, R.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chand, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Parsad, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Spot blotch</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Bipolaris sorokiniana</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cochliobolus sativus</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Wheat</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Triticum aestivum</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germplasm</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Yield</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Resistance</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>heat tolerance</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Seven hundred twenty-nine lines of diverse wheat germplasm lines were evaluated in eight locations of three countries (India, Nepal and Bangladesh) of South Asia for 5 years (1999&amp;ndash;2000 to 2003&amp;ndash;2004) through Eastern Gangetic Plains Screening Nursery (EGPSN) organized by CIMMYT South Asia, Nepal, for agronomic performance and tolerance to spot blotch of wheat. Each year, the number of lines represented a new set of 150 lines that included six common checks and a different local check at each of the eight locations. One hundred and five lines, 21 in each year, advanced from EGPSN were also tested for 5 years (2000&amp;ndash;2001 to 2004&amp;ndash;2005) in five locations of South Asia through Eastern Gangetic Plains Yield Trials (EGPYT) to verify spot blotch tolerance and superior yield performance of the selected germplasm. Many lines yielded significantly more than the best check and possessed high levels of spot blotch resistance under warm humid environments of South Asia. The most promising 25 lines have been listed as sources of strong resistance, with 9 lines better yielding than the best resistant check PBW 343 in fewer days to maturity. Most of these superior lines represented elite CIMMYT germplasm and around half were derived from Kauz and Veery. The line EGPYT 67, Kauz//Kauz/Star/3/Prinia/4/Milan/Kauz, was the best for spot blotch resistance, yield, days to maturity, and 1000 grain weight (TKW). The next two lines in the order of merit were EGPYT 84 (Mrng/Buc//Blo/Pvn/3/Pjb 81) and EGPYT 69 (Chirya3/Pastor). The results demonstrate that additional spot blotch resistant wheat genotypes with high grain yield and TKW, and early maturity, have become available as a result of the regional and international collaboration in South Asia.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:03Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:12:03Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2007</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2569</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>India</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1269750</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Nepal</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1282988</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Bangladesh</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1210997</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Nepal</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/1282988</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Asia</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255147</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2569</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2569</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:06:11Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>