<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The adoption of soil conservation technology in El Salvador: Linking productivity and conservation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Saín, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barreto, H.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>El Salvador</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil conservation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Plant production</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Economic environment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Economic viability</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Innovation adoption</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil conservation practices were successfully disseminated and adopted among farmers in Guaymango, El Salvador, whereas farmers in two similar areas failed to adopt them. Adoption was successful in Guaymango for two reasons. First, a recommendation was developed that combined both productivity-improving and soil conservation components. Second these components were linked by economic and institutional incentives that encouraged adoption of both components. Issues crucial to long-term success of soil conservation recommendations are discussed, particularly the need for the recommendation to be compatible with the farming system and effective in minimizing soil degradation. Potent-idl implications for research, extension, and policy are examined, with emphasis on technical requirements for developing system-management recommendations embodying productivity and conservation components</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-05T15:45:22Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-05T15:45:22Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>1996</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1407</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1407</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1407</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_5</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613914</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:35Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>