<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of genetic factors influencing the developmental rate of globally important CIMMYT wheat cultivars</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Beem, J. Van</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mohler, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lukman, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ginkel, M. Van</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>William, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crossa, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Worland, A.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>The rate at which wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) reaches anthesis and other developmental stages depends largely on the variation of three major factors: vernalization (Vrn), photoperiod (Ppd), and earliness per se (Eps). The objectives of this study were to characterize a set of genotypes for the presence of developmental genes and their potential association to adaptability and to identify diagnostic molecular markers for the vernalization gene Vrn-D1. Fifty-one genotypes were crossed with testers containing known Vrn and Ppd genes. To determine earliness per se and its interaction with temperature, genotypes were vernalized for 8 wk and placed in a 24-h photoperiod regime at two temperatures. To validate molecular markers for Vrn-D1, the cultivars were genotyped with closely linked SSR markers Xgwm292-5D and Xgwm212-5D. Segregation analysis on F2 populations of field-grown plants showed that Vrn-D1 was present in 66% of the cultivars, while Vrn-A1, Vrn-B1, and Vrn4 were found in 41, 39, and 8% of the lines, respectively, either solely or in combination with other Vrn genes. A low percentage of cultivars appeared to have a constitutive genetic character for early flowering (Eps), while most of the cultivars may have temperature-sensitive genes that respond to local environmental changes. Vrn-D1 was reliably detected in 76.5% of the genotypes using the 215-bp allele of microsatellite marker Xgwm292-5D, whereas Xgwm212-5D did not reveal sufficient allelic variation within the tested wheats</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:25Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:02:25Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2005</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/1683</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>1683</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_1683</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_8</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613917</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_2</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613911</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:36Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>