<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparing consumer preferences for color and nutritional quality in maize: application of a semi-double-bound logistic model on urban consumers in Kenya</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>De Groote, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kimenju, S.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>White maize</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Kenya</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biofortification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Contingent valuation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Consumer preferences for white maize in East and Southern Africa concerns developers of maize biofortified with provitamin A carotenoids, since carotenoids impart a yellow or orange coloration. Urban consumers&amp;rsquo; willingness to pay (WTP) for yellow maize was estimated, using a semi-double-bounded logistic model, based on a survey of 600 maize consumers in Nairobi, Kenya, at posho mills, kiosks and supermarkets. Consumers showed a strong preference for white maize. Only a minority would buy yellow maize at the same price as white maize, and fewer consumers in the posho mills (24%) and kiosks (19%) than in the supermarkets (34%) would do so. On average, consumers need a price discount of 37% to accept yellow maize. This discount was less at the posho mills (35%) and kiosks (37%) than in the supermarkets (48%). Most respondents (76%) were aware of the existence of fortified meal and the generally showed an interest. The average premium for fortified maize was much less than the discount for yellow: 5.9% for those aware and 7.4% for those unaware. Consumer preferences were influenced by socioeconomic factors such as gender, education, income and ethnic background. Women have a stronger preference for both white maize and fortified maize than men, and consumers with more education have a stronger preference for white. Income decreases the WTP for yellow maize as well as the price elasticity, but increases the WTP for fortified maize. Consumers originating from Western Kenya have a lower preference for white, while those from Central Kenya had a stronger preference for fortified maize.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:39Z</dc:date>
  <dc:date>2013-06-07T21:09:39Z</dc:date>
  <dc:pubDate>2008</dc:pubDate>
  <dc:type>Journal article</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10883/2146</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>English</dc:language>
  <dc:rights>CIMMYT manages Intellectual Assets as International Public Goods. The user is free to download, print, store and share this work. In case you want to translate or create any other derivative work and share or distribute such translation/derivative work, please contact CIMMYT-Knowledge-Center@cgiar.org indicating the work you want to use and the kind of use you intend; CIMMYT will contact you with the sutable license for that purpose.</dc:rights>
  <dc:geotag>Kenya</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/192950</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Kenya</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/192950</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Africa</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/6255146</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Kenya</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/192950</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Kenya</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/192950</dc:geonames>
  <dc:geotag>Kenya</dc:geotag>
  <dc:geonames>http://sws.geonames.org/192950</dc:geonames>
  <dc:domainid>10883</dc:domainid>
  <dc:cdocid>2146</dc:cdocid>
  <dc:apiid>10883_2146</dc:apiid>
  <dc:cset>com_10883_1</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>1403840553</dc:setid>
  <dc:cset>col_10883_7</dc:cset>
  <dc:setid>403613916</dc:setid>
  <dc:updated_date>2016-01-22T23:05:54Z</dc:updated_date>
  <dc:handler>http://repository.cimmyt.org/oai/request</dc:handler>
</oai_dc:dc>